<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Degreestory on eyeofparadox.com [eyeofparadox.wordpress.com] to eyeofparadox.github.io</title>
    <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/categories/degreestory/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Degreestory on eyeofparadox.com [eyeofparadox.wordpress.com] to eyeofparadox.github.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://eyeofparadox.github.io/categories/degreestory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bridging the Gap: A DegreeStory</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2016/08/2016-08-25-bridging-the-gap-a-degreestory/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2016/08/2016-08-25-bridging-the-gap-a-degreestory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Original publication: November 6, 2013&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Re: University of Phoenix Online&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Associate of Arts in Business&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bachelor of Science in Information Technology for Visual Communications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am the fifth of seven children, and was an advanced placement student in Art, English and Drama in High School. I have always had a knack for art, an urge to write and a flair for dramatics, so I always expected to end up as an artist, author or actor. I even got an early taste of college the summer after my freshman year in High School, on a 3/4 summer scholarship to the Academy of Art in San Francisco. That experience taught me that talent has to be backed up by hard work and sacrifice. I was not a perfect 4.0 student, but I was the first in the family to go off to college. I longed to go to a real art school, and was even offered a modest scholarship to the Savannah College of Art and Design&amp;ndash;but my parents could really only afford to send me to a State University. I learned that Humboldt State had a good Drama program and&amp;ndash;confident my own talent would carry me through any Art program at the state level&amp;ndash;I chose HSU.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fair and Sound: DegreeStory Replies</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2016/08/2016-08-25-fair-and-sound-degreestory-replies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2016/08/2016-08-25-fair-and-sound-degreestory-replies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Original publication: December 7, 2013&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Re: University of Phoenix Online&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Associate of Arts in Business&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bachelor of Science in Information Technology for Visual Communications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;article-1---100-words-answering-the-question&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Article #1 - 100 words answering the question:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;is-your-pay-fair&#34;&gt;Is your pay fair?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;fair-but-not-very-fair&#34;&gt;Fair, But Not &lt;em&gt;Very&lt;/em&gt; Fair&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are dozens of great lines in “The Princess Bride” like “Never go up against a Sicilian when Death is on the line” or “Hello! My name is Inigo Montoya. You killed my father. Prepare to die.” The one that holds the most truth, however, is, “Life isn’t fair, Princess. Anyone who says otherwise is trying to sell something.” What is true about life is true about work. I have never objected to working for a living, but as often as not I’ve found myself in a situation where I was living only to work. I’m an artist and a writer, so I am constantly driven to create—but I’ve rarely been lucky enough to get paid for my art or writing. So, I usually had a full time job, or two or three part time or contract jobs just to pay the bills. I would spend eight hours at work, as much as 3 hours communing to and from work, and another eight hours working on projects at home. I would get a few hours of sleep, and do it all again the next day, squeezing meals in when I had half an hour to spare.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
