<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Time on eyeofparadox.com [eyeofparadox.wordpress.com] to eyeofparadox.github.io</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/categories/time/</link><description>Recent content in Time on eyeofparadox.com [eyeofparadox.wordpress.com] to eyeofparadox.github.io</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://eyeofparadox.github.io/categories/time/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Physics in a Distributed, Process Driven, Information-Based Universe</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2025/11/physics-in-a-distributed-process-driven-information-based-universe/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2025/11/physics-in-a-distributed-process-driven-information-based-universe/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implications of Division by Zero and Point Paradox&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thought for the day&lt;/strong&gt;: My mind wandered back to division by zero and it suddenly struck me that, if applicable in nature, it would be the point where a value ceases to be &lt;em&gt;quanta&lt;/em&gt; and becomes &lt;em&gt;qualia&lt;/em&gt;. I did not see it for a while. I got to it by thinking about what&amp;rsquo;s hidden in plain sight in the concepts of quantum mechanics, and remembering a simple-but-paradoxical description of a hypersphere as &amp;ldquo;a sphere whose surface is nowhere, its focus is everywhere, and its radius infinite&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Examples of the 4th Dimension</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2018/09/examples-of-the-4th-dimension/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2018/09/examples-of-the-4th-dimension/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This is a thought that just popped into my head after reviewing my last post. Right off the top of my head, I picked out two candidates for the fourth dimension of space; Scale and State.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The underlying principle used to distinguish them was a concept that is spatial in nature, that lies beyond the immediate scope of a volume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technically speaking, a four dimensional space can theoretically contain an infinite number of volumes, much the way three dimensional space can potentially contain an infinite number of surfaces; what we typically experience as the expression of two dimensionality.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Musings On Physics &amp;amp; Metaphysics</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2018/09/musings-on-physics-metaphysics/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2018/09/musings-on-physics-metaphysics/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A lot of time has passed since I had the impulse to post anything; that does not mean I stopped writing my thoughts down! I came across the following on a buried tab in my Notepad++ application. I have tons of random notes like this, and often do nothing with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean, they&amp;rsquo;re not really intended for the average reader. You might not be able to follow them, and I don&amp;rsquo;t really know what parts need further elaboration for you to grok them. Even so, I can still throw them out there and hope that you will comment or request explanations if you need them.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>A Point about Paradox</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2010/12/a-point-about-paradox/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2010/12/a-point-about-paradox/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In the eternal moment, the past and the future are simply a matter of perspective and the past can be influenced by overlapping reinforcement or the intent of the resolving future. A time paradox is a self-informing sequence within a point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The classic grandfather paradox assumes that time is linear, ignoring the fact that the appearance of a person from the future is an unprecedented event at that point in the past. It also ignores the consequences of his absence from the point of his departure in the future.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Awakening</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/06/111/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/06/111/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I have pointed out before that my struggle with gender dysphoria prompted me to search in all directions for a solution to being born in the wrong body, and the determination with which I pursued that goal in spite of all doubts and discouragements &amp;ndash; even attempts to accept things the way they were, adapting to and adopting the identity imposed on me by circumstances &amp;ndash; says a lot about me, and even about what I ultimately concluded. My existence may be supported by reality, the physical, chemical, biological and sociological fabric out of which we all seem to be spun, but none of these things are me. I exist in my mind and that is why the way I perceive myself in my own mind can not only contradict my physical form, but trump it in importance to my survival. I have heard the theories and arguments on nature versus nurture and taking my own experience into consideration I can say that there are elements in both that can help shape who you are, but only by presenting the options or stimulus necessary for you to determine who you are. I cannot tell you if this is a process of creation or revelation; it feels like both. I am the driving and defining force within my own mind; my mind is the structure and articulation of my soul.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Damage is Done</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/05/the-damage-is-done/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/05/the-damage-is-done/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I wonder what is going to happen next. I wonder if I can hold it together to get a job and move out on my own. I wonder if I can manage to hold on to that job and support myself. I wonder, because I am not really wanted where I am. The only support I can count on, the support of my family and friends, is conditional. It always has been. It has always been conditional on me finding a way to get steady on my own two feet. The irony of that always brings a smile of agony. I know what they want, and that they want it for me, for me to become independent. It is something I do want. The problem is that it leaves me alone inside a life that holds absolutely no meaning for me. This person that I pretend to be, because he means something to his friends and family, means nothing to me. He does not mean enough, to the people who employ him, to have any purpose. He can be replaced by anyone and cannot compete with the living.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Time in a Distributed, Process Driven, Information-Based Universe</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/07/time-in-a-distributed-process-driven-information-based-universe/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/07/time-in-a-distributed-process-driven-information-based-universe/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In order to understand time it becomes necessary to ask if time is an objective or subjective medium. To be clear, by considering time subjectively I do not mean simply in terms of our subjective perception of time. The question asks if time is absolute, and thus events at different points in time persist in their own frame of reference with a constant relative position in time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, it asks if there are actual positions in and structure to time. The alternative, subjective time, deals with the concept of time as being functional, an operation upon the objective structure of matter and energy in space like the constant balancing of an equation in which there is no actual time, just a present state of the equation.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Is there really such a thing as the present?</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/07/is-there-really-such-a-thing-as-the-present/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/07/is-there-really-such-a-thing-as-the-present/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Is there really such a thing as time? That is a question it is helpful to ask in order to address what we call the present. That is because our experience of time is completely subjective and because everything we are is dependent on that peculiar subjectivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time is what we derive from the ceaseless transformation that is part of awareness, consciousness, thought, perception, action and reaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time is our measure of the dynamic quality of existence that compliments the static quality of existence the latter of which allows the world and ourselves to be manifest.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>