<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Absolute on eyeofparadox.com [eyeofparadox.wordpress.com] to eyeofparadox.github.io</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/categories/absolute/</link><description>Recent content in Absolute on eyeofparadox.com [eyeofparadox.wordpress.com] to eyeofparadox.github.io</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://eyeofparadox.github.io/categories/absolute/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Physics in a Distributed, Process Driven, Information-Based Universe</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2025/11/physics-in-a-distributed-process-driven-information-based-universe/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2025/11/physics-in-a-distributed-process-driven-information-based-universe/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implications of Division by Zero and Point Paradox&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thought for the day&lt;/strong&gt;: My mind wandered back to division by zero and it suddenly struck me that, if applicable in nature, it would be the point where a value ceases to be &lt;em&gt;quanta&lt;/em&gt; and becomes &lt;em&gt;qualia&lt;/em&gt;. I did not see it for a while. I got to it by thinking about what&amp;rsquo;s hidden in plain sight in the concepts of quantum mechanics, and remembering a simple-but-paradoxical description of a hypersphere as &amp;ldquo;a sphere whose surface is nowhere, its focus is everywhere, and its radius infinite&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>All or Nothing; Division by Zero</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2022/10/all-or-nothing-division-by-zero/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2022/10/all-or-nothing-division-by-zero/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;If you divide by nothing, in one sense, you get nothing. In another sense, you are left with everything. However much there is to divide, all of it remains - undivided. The remainder is everything. To count it all, however, you must divide it up into discrete quantities. Of course, you can keep dividing it into smaller and smaller parts, each of which is increasingly infinitesimal. As you do so, the number you are calculating approaches infinity. This is the paradox of division by zero.  &lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>A Spark</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/09/a-spark/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/09/a-spark/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;My eyes opened and this is what I saw. You can in yourself be anything you desire. You create yourself from a point. You define your own existence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A soul defines itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What words cannot define, they can characterize, so that the truth may be recognized as it is encountered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The existence of a soul is absolute, at once all and nothing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The qualities of a soul are both infinite and eternal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A soul is not a question, nor is a soul an answer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A soul is a statement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A soul is an expression, a unique, individual creation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I gazed in wonder, I realized that even before a soul embraces the awareness of other souls, the darkness of a soul embraces the light of other souls, filling the emptiness of its existence with the certainty of others, both as a foundation for its own reality, and a medium for the realization of its self.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Absolute Truth</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/10/the-absolute-truth/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/10/the-absolute-truth/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The best representation of a thing is the thing itself and yet there are things that we experience great difficulty recognizing in their true form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The truth is one of those things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In speaking of the truth, what we have is a word&amp;ndash;and as a representation of a thing, a word provides a label for a concept that is meaningless without an accurate understanding of what the concept represents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding the true meaning of truth is a challenge because it calls upon itself for validation, which is a logical fallacy. Or is it?&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>