<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gender on eyeofparadox.com [eyeofparadox.wordpress.com] to eyeofparadox.github.io</title>
    <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/tags/gender/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gender on eyeofparadox.com [eyeofparadox.wordpress.com] to eyeofparadox.github.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://eyeofparadox.github.io/tags/gender/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>It Takes a Village to Break a Child</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/07/2009-07-24-it-takes-a-village-to-break-a-child/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/07/2009-07-24-it-takes-a-village-to-break-a-child/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I do not often get comments on my blog; if I exclude the pingbacks, spam and my own replies, I&amp;rsquo;ve received twenty-two comments from ten different individuals since I started the eye of paradox two years ago. Four of those people have identified themselves as transgendered, and like every transgendered person I&amp;rsquo;ve known, it has affected their lives as bad or worse than mine and I do not have to explain myself to them to be understood. For a long time, I&amp;rsquo;ve understood that this condition is difficult or even impossible for people who have not experienced it to comprehend. In order to live with normal people, the &amp;ldquo;cisgendered&amp;rdquo; if I use the term that&amp;rsquo;s come into use to describe those who identify with their birth sex, I&amp;rsquo;ve had to go to incredible lengths to comprehend and empathize with them. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried many, many times to find a way to describe what it feels like to live with this condition, hoping to make it easier for my family and friends to understand me. As I mentioned, I do not always like what comes out when I write on this topic, because it is a very intensely emotional issue and intensely emotional writing just encourages people to accuse me of being mellow-dramatic. I honestly expect most people to be driven away by the things I have written. Growing up, it did not take me long to learn how incredibly unsympathetic most people are about this issue. I was never asked to explain myself. With the exception of my adopted mother, who confronted me when I was six to ask if I wanted to be a girl, no one ever asked me why I acted like a girl. By the time she asked, I knew better than to admit it, since every other time someone noticed I was just slapped, spanked, or jerked around while being criticized for acting like a girl and being commanded to stop. That does not mean I was not asking myself why I acted like a girl. Even though the question was often on my mind, the only answer that ever rang true was the one that the facts denied.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
