<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Death on eyeofparadox.com [eyeofparadox.wordpress.com] to eyeofparadox.github.io</title>
    <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/categories/death/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Death on eyeofparadox.com [eyeofparadox.wordpress.com] to eyeofparadox.github.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://eyeofparadox.github.io/categories/death/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Does it ever get better?</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2016/04/2016-04-06-does-it-ever-get-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2016/04/2016-04-06-does-it-ever-get-better/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am well acquainted with the depths of despair; that place where words hurt in every way and never more than when they give the faintest glimmer of the only thing that could possibly be worse than despair:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hope&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hope makes you drag yourself through the hell you’re trapped in when you’re so broken it’s a miracle you can even move.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hope makes you choke down the agony and anguish, and endure whatever punishment life heaps on top of it, for the unlikely and virtually impossible chance you will survive the pain long enough to discover what it’s like to be free of it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It Takes a Village to Break a Child</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/07/2009-07-24-it-takes-a-village-to-break-a-child/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/07/2009-07-24-it-takes-a-village-to-break-a-child/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I do not often get comments on my blog; if I exclude the pingbacks, spam and my own replies, I&amp;rsquo;ve received twenty-two comments from ten different individuals since I started the eye of paradox two years ago. Four of those people have identified themselves as transgendered, and like every transgendered person I&amp;rsquo;ve known, it has affected their lives as bad or worse than mine and I do not have to explain myself to them to be understood. For a long time, I&amp;rsquo;ve understood that this condition is difficult or even impossible for people who have not experienced it to comprehend. In order to live with normal people, the &amp;ldquo;cisgendered&amp;rdquo; if I use the term that&amp;rsquo;s come into use to describe those who identify with their birth sex, I&amp;rsquo;ve had to go to incredible lengths to comprehend and empathize with them. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried many, many times to find a way to describe what it feels like to live with this condition, hoping to make it easier for my family and friends to understand me. As I mentioned, I do not always like what comes out when I write on this topic, because it is a very intensely emotional issue and intensely emotional writing just encourages people to accuse me of being mellow-dramatic. I honestly expect most people to be driven away by the things I have written. Growing up, it did not take me long to learn how incredibly unsympathetic most people are about this issue. I was never asked to explain myself. With the exception of my adopted mother, who confronted me when I was six to ask if I wanted to be a girl, no one ever asked me why I acted like a girl. By the time she asked, I knew better than to admit it, since every other time someone noticed I was just slapped, spanked, or jerked around while being criticized for acting like a girl and being commanded to stop. That does not mean I was not asking myself why I acted like a girl. Even though the question was often on my mind, the only answer that ever rang true was the one that the facts denied.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Point Penetrating Points Overlapping</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/07/2009-07-22-point-penetrating-points-overlapping/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/07/2009-07-22-point-penetrating-points-overlapping/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A number of my posts, particularly the ones dealing with transgender issues in my life, have been written on a long, dark night of the soul. It can be difficult to come back and read what I&amp;rsquo;ve posted and resist the urge to delete what I&amp;rsquo;ve written, because of how dark they are. I have moments when I think, if ever a family member happened to read them, some of what I&amp;rsquo;ve written could really hurt them. That was never the intention, and yet, there is a ring of truth to the posts I am not able to deny. It is an unfortunate fact that I&amp;rsquo;ve been hurt a great deal by people who never meant me harm because of things neither I nor they had any control over. It is not their fault that efforts to encourage my growth and development as a son or brother caused me so much pain; they were simply responding to what they perceived me to be. Our current society is the end product of thousands of generations of people struggling through life trying to make sense out of it. If that resulted in the division of human traits into masculine and feminine, and if the cultivation of gender roles led to a society that could not understand that there was a difference between the things that make people who they are and the things that make them what they are, it is not possible to assign fault or blame to any specific group, let alone a given person. As much as it would have made a difference in my life to have been raised among people who were more perceptive, or in a society that was more accepting of individual differences, I would still have grown up with the more difficult problem of being a girl in a boy&amp;rsquo;s body.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hidden in Plain Sight</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/07/2009-07-07-hidden-in-plain-sight/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/07/2009-07-07-hidden-in-plain-sight/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On April 27, 2008 at 12:36 am, I began a post &amp;ndash; this post, actually &amp;ndash; but got no further than the title. I don&amp;rsquo;t know if that was because that title summed up my feelings so well that there was no point to writing any further about what was on my mind. Yesterday, those words came back to me at the conclusion of &lt;a href=&#34;http://eyeofparadox.com/2009/07/06/a-glimpse-into-the-eye-of-paradox/&#34;&gt;A Glimpse into the Eye of Paradox&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve always thought of the truth as something that is hidden in plain sight, and approached it as something that we take so much for granted we really don&amp;rsquo;t know what to do with it. One might as well say that the truth that can be put into words is not the truth. Communication is more a matter of interpretation, and there is no singularity to interpretation. The truth is out there, and every time we encounter it, we are seeing it from a limited point of view. When we come across it again from a different point of view, we still recognize it as the truth but it not only appears different, we ourselves understand it in a different context.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Awakening</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/06/2009-06-30-111/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/06/2009-06-30-111/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have pointed out before that my struggle with gender dysphoria prompted me to search in all directions for a solution to being born in the wrong body, and the determination with which I pursued that goal in spite of all doubts and discouragements &amp;ndash; even attempts to accept things the way they were, adapting to and adopting the identity imposed on me by circumstances &amp;ndash; says a lot about me, and even about what I ultimately concluded. My existence may be supported by reality, the physical, chemical, biological and sociological fabric out of which we all seem to be spun, but none of these things are me. I exist in my mind and that is why the way I perceive myself in my own mind can not only contradict my physical form, but trump it in importance to my survival. I have heard the theories and arguments on nature versus nurture and taking my own experience into consideration I can say that there are elements in both that can help shape who you are, but only by presenting the options or stimulus necessary for you to determine who you are. I cannot tell you if this is a process of creation or revelation; it feels like both. I am the driving and defining force within my own mind; my mind is the structure and articulation of my soul.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Paradox of Death</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/2007-08-24-the-paradox-of-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/2007-08-24-the-paradox-of-death/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is more to this, to existing, than meets the eye. It is its own prerequisite and it hurts think about why or how. The only thing that hurts more is trying to make sense &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; existing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But, given our circumstances, we can&amp;rsquo;t really afford to take it for granted. By a certain age, we know that death awaits, but what does it really mean, in practice?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Its not a box you can just think you way out of, but its always safe to assume there is no valid alternative to &lt;em&gt;being.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
