<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Legend on eyeofparadox.com [eyeofparadox.wordpress.com] to eyeofparadox.github.io</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/categories/legend/</link><description>Recent content in Legend on eyeofparadox.com [eyeofparadox.wordpress.com] to eyeofparadox.github.io</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://eyeofparadox.github.io/categories/legend/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Avonlea - Highlands - Island Dawn</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2019/06/eye-of-paradox-annex-artstation-com-avonlea-highlands-island/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2019/06/eye-of-paradox-annex-artstation-com-avonlea-highlands-island/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.artstation.com/artwork/oOBBVL"&gt;&lt;img src="images/david-roberson-avonlea-island-dawn-2x-anamorphic.jpg" alt="david-roberson-avonlea-island-dawn-2x-anamorphic"&gt;ArtStation Post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A quick preface to this post, Child of Paradox already encompasses a number of story arcs, and each thread has gained it&amp;rsquo;s own heading. Those references help me sort through reams of material quickly in my head, but won&amp;rsquo;t make much sense beyond tantelizing hints at the referenced arc&amp;rsquo;s plot. So, this is one of those glimpses that will leave you wondering, more than spoiled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building on notes for the reboot of Child of Paradox, the notion for today is to change the sequence of the following threads: &lt;em&gt;Hunger and Thirst&lt;/em&gt; can be assigned to Dawn (Arden Ava Nova), as a preface to the inception of Avonlea (Morgan Avon Ova Lea); Predator and Prey can be a consequence of the &lt;em&gt;Ghost/Demon Within&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Slain Lover&lt;/em&gt; threads; &lt;em&gt;Inheritance and Engagement&lt;/em&gt; can be a strand linking the &lt;em&gt;Goddess and Girl&lt;/em&gt; threads with &lt;em&gt;Hunger and Thirst&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Daughter Self&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>A Goddess &amp;amp; A Girl [SPOILER]</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2019/06/a-goddess-a-girl-spoiler/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2019/06/a-goddess-a-girl-spoiler/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve set out a number of approaches to Child of Paradox over the years. Even recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve danced around my personal relationship with the evolution of the story, trying to deal with it in the characters&amp;rsquo; context. I have had to know the whole thing to handle the paradoxical influences, in contrast to the perspectives of both readers and characters. Warning of spoilers ahead, here&amp;rsquo;s a glimpse into the story behind the story: In addition to other notions I&amp;rsquo;ve shared, this is a slightly different take on the story. The premise begins with the dream within my nightmare. Within me, my ideal self retreated from reality propping up an alter ego that is in essence a demon. My dream was always a search for a way to be myself. My nightmare was being trapped in a world where I didn&amp;rsquo;t really exist. My demon was originally an angel, but in pursuit of my dream, it became possessive and took a key role in reshaping my dream into a reality where I could exist, though I did not live in it.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Aeirn</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2018/10/background-notes-aeirn/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2018/10/background-notes-aeirn/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve spent the past week or so going through old notes, gathering some of the History and Legends of Aeirn, and sorting out bits of plot, to figure out where Child of Paradox will begin. There is much more to dig through, but this much is pretty solid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aeirn — A world of magic and technology&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aeirn was originally conceived as a world with a magical and technological heritage. The common assumption, that a magical society would not develop technology and a technological society would discourage the emergence of magic, is debated in front of or with the protagonist at some point. She points out that the two legacies were founded in separate eras and in different parts of the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>