<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Social-Stratification on eyeofparadox.com [eyeofparadox.wordpress.com] to eyeofparadox.github.io</title>
    <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/categories/social-stratification/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Social-Stratification on eyeofparadox.com [eyeofparadox.wordpress.com] to eyeofparadox.github.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://eyeofparadox.github.io/categories/social-stratification/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A True Identity is Nothing to Fear</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/05/2008-05-14-a-true-identity-is-nothing-to-fear/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/05/2008-05-14-a-true-identity-is-nothing-to-fear/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The response I received to my last post, &lt;a href=&#34;http://eyeofparadox.com/2008/05/11/conundrum/&#34;&gt;Conundrum&lt;/a&gt;, prompted me to check out the recent posts of the people who commented or posted blogs in the transgender category yesterday. As a result, I became aware of the outcry against the appointment of Dr. Kenneth Zucker, Dr. Ray Blanchard, and J. Michael Bailey, by the American Psychiatric Association (APA), to the work group responsible for revising the entry for Gender Identity Disorder (GID) in the Manual for Diagnosis of Mental Disorders. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://genderoutlaw.wordpress.com/2008/05/11/the-apa-appointment-of-zucker-et-al-and-gender-variant-children/&#34;&gt;first blog&lt;/a&gt; I read on the subject, posted by Gender Outlaw, struck a very personal chord with me. In addition to being transgendered, I was put up for adoption when I was four and spent a year in foster care while the state attempted to contact my biological father so that he might claim his custody rights. It was during my time in foster care that I was terrorized out of identifying myself as a girl and learned to keep my true identity a secret. It took time to learn how to restrain my natural impulses and act like a boy, and the threat of abandonment and rejection was used to reinforce &amp;ldquo;correct&amp;rdquo; behavior. By the time I was adopted, this conditioning had scarred me for life, rendering me incapable of trusting anyone with my true thoughts and feelings. When my new family noticed my feminine traits and confronted me with questions about my behavior, or offered even a mild rebuke for &amp;ldquo;acting like a girl&amp;rdquo; I was consumed with that fear of rejection and lied to deflect any suspicions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Social Stratification</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/2007-08-22-the-impact-of-social-stratification/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/2007-08-22-the-impact-of-social-stratification/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re all human. None of us have a say in what circumstances we are born. Pretty much any other characteristic by which people can be defined produces some form of social stratification.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thinking about it boggles the mind.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve grown up with the ideas of caste and class, and tried to understand how anyone can willingly accept being &amp;ldquo;put in their place&amp;rdquo; by the people around them. In the end, I think it all comes down to the perception of power, the ways in which circumstances can be used to dominate society.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
