<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>End-of-the-World on eyeofparadox.com [eyeofparadox.wordpress.com] to eyeofparadox.github.io</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/categories/end-of-the-world/</link><description>Recent content in End-of-the-World on eyeofparadox.com [eyeofparadox.wordpress.com] to eyeofparadox.github.io</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://eyeofparadox.github.io/categories/end-of-the-world/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Does it ever get better?</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2016/04/does-it-ever-get-better/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2016/04/does-it-ever-get-better/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I am well acquainted with the depths of despair; that place where words hurt in every way and never more than when they give the faintest glimmer of the only thing that could possibly be worse than despair:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hope&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope makes you drag yourself through the hell you’re trapped in when you’re so broken it’s a miracle you can even move.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope makes you choke down the agony and anguish, and endure whatever punishment life heaps on top of it, for the unlikely and virtually impossible chance you will survive the pain long enough to discover what it’s like to be free of it.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Damage is Done</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/05/the-damage-is-done/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/05/the-damage-is-done/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I wonder what is going to happen next. I wonder if I can hold it together to get a job and move out on my own. I wonder if I can manage to hold on to that job and support myself. I wonder, because I am not really wanted where I am. The only support I can count on, the support of my family and friends, is conditional. It always has been. It has always been conditional on me finding a way to get steady on my own two feet. The irony of that always brings a smile of agony. I know what they want, and that they want it for me, for me to become independent. It is something I do want. The problem is that it leaves me alone inside a life that holds absolutely no meaning for me. This person that I pretend to be, because he means something to his friends and family, means nothing to me. He does not mean enough, to the people who employ him, to have any purpose. He can be replaced by anyone and cannot compete with the living.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Paradox of Death</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/the-paradox-of-death/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/the-paradox-of-death/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;There is more to this, to existing, than meets the eye. It is its own prerequisite and it hurts think about why or how. The only thing that hurts more is trying to make sense &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; existing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, given our circumstances, we can&amp;rsquo;t really afford to take it for granted. By a certain age, we know that death awaits, but what does it really mean, in practice?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its not a box you can just think you way out of, but its always safe to assume there is no valid alternative to &lt;em&gt;being.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Impact of Social Stratification</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/the-impact-of-social-stratification/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/the-impact-of-social-stratification/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re all human. None of us have a say in what circumstances we are born. Pretty much any other characteristic by which people can be defined produces some form of social stratification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thinking about it boggles the mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve grown up with the ideas of caste and class, and tried to understand how anyone can willingly accept being &amp;ldquo;put in their place&amp;rdquo; by the people around them. In the end, I think it all comes down to the perception of power, the ways in which circumstances can be used to dominate society.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Take a Moment to Reflect</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/take-a-moment-to-reflect/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/take-a-moment-to-reflect/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Even with the best intentions no one has the right to impose a system of thought or action on anyone against their will. Ironically, that is exactly what has happened to all of us as we were born into this world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is in some ways no different than being born into slavery, in the sense that we come into the world having no say in the system that will govern our lives, and we spend our most vulnerable years being programmed to become obedient citizens and uphold the status quo.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>