<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on eyeofparadox.wordpress.echo</title>
    <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on eyeofparadox.wordpress.echo</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 20:57:58 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alpha</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/alpha/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 20:57:58 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/alpha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the first .md post, cmdline generated and rendered through Hugo and GitHub Pages.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WordPress → GitHub Pages Notes</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2025/11/2025-11-19-wordpress--github-pages-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2025/11/2025-11-19-wordpress--github-pages-notes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;export&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Export&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you click the export button in wp-admin/tools, WordPress will create an &lt;strong&gt;XML&lt;/strong&gt; file for you to save to your computer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This format, which is called &lt;strong&gt;WordPress eXtended RSS&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;WXR&lt;/strong&gt;, will contain your posts, pages, comments, custom fields, categories, and tags.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve saved the download file, you can use the Import function in another WordPress installation to import the content from this site.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you’re going to be using a &lt;strong&gt;WordPress&lt;/strong&gt;-powered site, download the &lt;strong&gt;wp-content&lt;/strong&gt; directory and the &lt;strong&gt;wp-config.php&lt;/strong&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Physics in a Distributed, Process Driven, Information-Based Universe</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2025/11/2025-11-18-physics-in-a-distributed-process-driven-information-based-universe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2025/11/2025-11-18-physics-in-a-distributed-process-driven-information-based-universe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implications of Division by Zero and Point Paradox&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thought for the day&lt;/strong&gt;: My mind wandered back to division by zero and it suddenly struck me that, if applicable in nature, it would be the point where a value ceases to be &lt;em&gt;quanta&lt;/em&gt; and becomes &lt;em&gt;qualia&lt;/em&gt;. I did not see it for a while. I got to it by thinking about what&amp;rsquo;s hidden in plain sight in the concepts of quantum mechanics, and remembering a simple-but-paradoxical description of a hypersphere as &amp;ldquo;a sphere whose surface is nowhere, its focus is everywhere, and its radius infinite&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proposed Doctrine of „ Notation</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2025/05/2025-05-26-proposed-doctrine-of-duo-comma-notation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2025/05/2025-05-26-proposed-doctrine-of-duo-comma-notation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction to the Doctrine of &lt;em&gt;&lt;code&gt;„&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/em&gt; Notation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The idea behind &lt;strong&gt;„&lt;/strong&gt; notation originated from a necessity—how do we create a &lt;strong&gt;concise, yet expressive&lt;/strong&gt; system for defining structured relationships between elements? Whether dealing with &lt;strong&gt;datasets, filenames, computational hierarchies, or exclusions&lt;/strong&gt;, conventional formats often lacked clarity or introduced unnecessary ambiguity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This notation emerged as a &lt;strong&gt;solution&lt;/strong&gt;, offering a way to &lt;strong&gt;track divisions, subsets, sequencing, and structured logic&lt;/strong&gt; in a simple yet powerful syntax.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>All or Nothing; Division by Zero</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2022/10/2022-10-10-all-or-nothing-division-by-zero/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2022/10/2022-10-10-all-or-nothing-division-by-zero/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you divide by nothing, in one sense, you get nothing. In another sense, you are left with everything. However much there is to divide, all of it remains - undivided. The remainder is everything. To count it all, however, you must divide it up into discrete quantities. Of course, you can keep dividing it into smaller and smaller parts, each of which is increasingly infinitesimal. As you do so, the number you are calculating approaches infinity. This is the paradox of division by zero.  &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Examples of the 4th Dimension</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2018/09/2018-09-16-examples-of-the-4th-dimension/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2018/09/2018-09-16-examples-of-the-4th-dimension/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a thought that just popped into my head after reviewing my last post. Right off the top of my head, I picked out two candidates for the fourth dimension of space; Scale and State.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The underlying principle used to distinguish them was a concept that is spatial in nature, that lies beyond the immediate scope of a volume.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Technically speaking, a four dimensional space can theoretically contain an infinite number of volumes, much the way three dimensional space can potentially contain an infinite number of surfaces; what we typically experience as the expression of two dimensionality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Musings On Physics &amp;amp; Metaphysics</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2018/09/2018-09-16-musings-on-physics-metaphysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2018/09/2018-09-16-musings-on-physics-metaphysics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A lot of time has passed since I had the impulse to post anything; that does not mean I stopped writing my thoughts down! I came across the following on a buried tab in my Notepad++ application. I have tons of random notes like this, and often do nothing with them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I mean, they&amp;rsquo;re not really intended for the average reader. You might not be able to follow them, and I don&amp;rsquo;t really know what parts need further elaboration for you to grok them. Even so, I can still throw them out there and hope that you will comment or request explanations if you need them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond My Grasp</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2016/08/2016-08-25-beyond-my-grasp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2016/08/2016-08-25-beyond-my-grasp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Advisory:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I sort of choke and swallow hard before posting an article like this on the eye of paradox, in spite of the fact that&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;I have a history of being rather candid about my experiences as a &amp;ldquo;transgendered&amp;rdquo; individual here and on deviantart. I know that many of these posts have the potential to hurt me, professionally, and yet they serve the essential and undeniable need for self-expression that is ultimately the only way I can justify my existence. I would not be surprised to find that these posts drive more people away than they ever manage to enlighten, and shade my other writing with a transferred contempt. I am sure many people who do read through them must think, &amp;ldquo;this has to be exaggerated,&amp;rdquo; though I must confess that my best effort to put these feelings into words fall short&amp;ndash;hence, I keep revisiting them, trying to vent the agony in &amp;ldquo;a whisper of hollow words to dress up the shattering, inarticulate screams of a forever breaking heart.&amp;rdquo; If you choose to read this, to know what I cannot allow myself to show on the surface, just know that I overcome this pain in every moment I manage to present that calm, composed facade. I am not looking for pity, and I can&amp;rsquo;t say I feel sorry for myself; I am not sorry to be me&amp;ndash;there is just no easy way to present myself to you.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bridging the Gap: A DegreeStory</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2016/08/2016-08-25-bridging-the-gap-a-degreestory/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2016/08/2016-08-25-bridging-the-gap-a-degreestory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Original publication: November 6, 2013&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Re: University of Phoenix Online&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Associate of Arts in Business&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bachelor of Science in Information Technology for Visual Communications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am the fifth of seven children, and was an advanced placement student in Art, English and Drama in High School. I have always had a knack for art, an urge to write and a flair for dramatics, so I always expected to end up as an artist, author or actor. I even got an early taste of college the summer after my freshman year in High School, on a 3/4 summer scholarship to the Academy of Art in San Francisco. That experience taught me that talent has to be backed up by hard work and sacrifice. I was not a perfect 4.0 student, but I was the first in the family to go off to college. I longed to go to a real art school, and was even offered a modest scholarship to the Savannah College of Art and Design&amp;ndash;but my parents could really only afford to send me to a State University. I learned that Humboldt State had a good Drama program and&amp;ndash;confident my own talent would carry me through any Art program at the state level&amp;ndash;I chose HSU.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fair and Sound: DegreeStory Replies</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2016/08/2016-08-25-fair-and-sound-degreestory-replies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2016/08/2016-08-25-fair-and-sound-degreestory-replies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Original publication: December 7, 2013&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Re: University of Phoenix Online&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Associate of Arts in Business&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bachelor of Science in Information Technology for Visual Communications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;article-1---100-words-answering-the-question&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Article #1 - 100 words answering the question:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;is-your-pay-fair&#34;&gt;Is your pay fair?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;fair-but-not-very-fair&#34;&gt;Fair, But Not &lt;em&gt;Very&lt;/em&gt; Fair&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are dozens of great lines in “The Princess Bride” like “Never go up against a Sicilian when Death is on the line” or “Hello! My name is Inigo Montoya. You killed my father. Prepare to die.” The one that holds the most truth, however, is, “Life isn’t fair, Princess. Anyone who says otherwise is trying to sell something.” What is true about life is true about work. I have never objected to working for a living, but as often as not I’ve found myself in a situation where I was living only to work. I’m an artist and a writer, so I am constantly driven to create—but I’ve rarely been lucky enough to get paid for my art or writing. So, I usually had a full time job, or two or three part time or contract jobs just to pay the bills. I would spend eight hours at work, as much as 3 hours communing to and from work, and another eight hours working on projects at home. I would get a few hours of sleep, and do it all again the next day, squeezing meals in when I had half an hour to spare.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poetry and Figurative Language Paper</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2016/08/2016-08-25-poetry-and-figurative-language-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2016/08/2016-08-25-poetry-and-figurative-language-paper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April 6, 2009&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENG 340 - Creative Writing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dr. Shari Muench, EdD.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A pen and a piece of paper might technically be the only “tools” a poet requires, but there are many “literary” tools at his (or her) disposal as well. In addition to imagination and a little flirtation with the Muse, a poet uses many other elements of writing to craft his (or her) messages to the heart and soul. This paper looks at the works of three great poets, three extraordinary poems, and explores the imagery, metaphors, rhyme and structure that make them so great. Examples from William Shakespeare’s sonnet, “When, in Disgrace with Fortune and Men’s Eyes” (Thiel, 2004, p.311), Robert Frost’s “The Road Not Taken” (Thiel, 2004, p.297), and Craig Raine’s, “A Martian Sends a Postcard Home” (Thiel, 2004, p.308) will be used to discuss the importance of figurative language in poetry and how it communicates to the reader.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taking Part in the Dance with our Eyes Closed</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2016/08/2016-08-20-taking-part-in-the-dance-with-our-eyes-closed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2016/08/2016-08-20-taking-part-in-the-dance-with-our-eyes-closed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Writing is the embodiment of aspiration.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It begins with the will to overcome the unanswerable statement of a blank page.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It proceeds in the blind ambition of being read and comprehended.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It strives to commit to a more permanent memory the thoughts and ideas of the writer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As often as not, the written word is as quirky and unreliable as any memory, easily lost or misplaced, often transcended by thoughts that spring in the wake of ages, be they moments or millennia.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Touch of Fear</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2016/08/2016-08-18-a-touch-of-fear-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2016/08/2016-08-18-a-touch-of-fear-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, all you need to say can be said in a few lines. This is one of the shortest posts I&amp;rsquo;ve ever made, but it speaks volumes!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Patience and Perseverance</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2016/08/2016-08-18-patience-and-perseverance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2016/08/2016-08-18-patience-and-perseverance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;em&gt;I have to preface this as the follow-up to &lt;strong&gt;The Price of Dreams&lt;/strong&gt;, and point out that it is over two years old now. Seems like a day, and a life-time ago. I&amp;rsquo;m sorry to say, that my life did not go on to a happy place, but for a moment it seemed like my fast slide into the abyss was stopped at the brink.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;by &lt;a href=&#34;http://avmorgan.deviantart.com/&#34;&gt;avmorgan&lt;/a&gt;, Jan 26, 2014, 3:53:02 PM&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;in Journals / Personal&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Does it ever get better?</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2016/04/2016-04-06-does-it-ever-get-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2016/04/2016-04-06-does-it-ever-get-better/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am well acquainted with the depths of despair; that place where words hurt in every way and never more than when they give the faintest glimmer of the only thing that could possibly be worse than despair:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hope&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hope makes you drag yourself through the hell you’re trapped in when you’re so broken it’s a miracle you can even move.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hope makes you choke down the agony and anguish, and endure whatever punishment life heaps on top of it, for the unlikely and virtually impossible chance you will survive the pain long enough to discover what it’s like to be free of it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do current theories on Black Holes address Forces other than Gravity?</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2014/01/2014-01-21-do-current-theories-on-black-holes-address-forces-other-than-gravity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2014/01/2014-01-21-do-current-theories-on-black-holes-address-forces-other-than-gravity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From time to time, I stumble across a question I have to stop and ask, but I am usually in the middle of something that needs to be done. So, I put it off for later, often forgetting to even write the question down. I know this one is going to come back to plague me, so I am putting it out there in the hopes I can come back and do some research on it later, while giving the random visitor to my site a chance to comment on it or point me toward a source with something to say about the subject.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s been a while...</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2014/01/2014-01-03-its-been-a-while/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2014/01/2014-01-03-its-been-a-while/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have spent the past few years chasing after The Job and sliding down to the point where I&amp;rsquo;m scrambling to just grab A job. It&amp;rsquo;s an old, familiar story, and the details aren&amp;rsquo;t really that important. For the sake of my blog, all that matters is that I have not had much time to put my thoughts down, and no time to review or post any that might have been worth sharing. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure when that will change, but I&amp;rsquo;m going to take a crack at it. There&amp;rsquo;s always the chance that my blog could open the door to some kind of paying work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Point about Paradox</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2010/12/2010-12-06-a-point-about-paradox/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2010/12/2010-12-06-a-point-about-paradox/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the eternal moment, the past and the future are simply a matter of perspective and the past can be influenced by overlapping reinforcement or the intent of the resolving future. A time paradox is a self-informing sequence within a point.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The classic grandfather paradox assumes that time is linear, ignoring the fact that the appearance of a person from the future is an unprecedented event at that point in the past. It also ignores the consequences of his absence from the point of his departure in the future.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is This It?</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/09/2009-09-27-is-this-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/09/2009-09-27-is-this-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was on my way home on Wednesday, September 23, 2009, with my dinner in hand, and I swear I just wanted to sit down and eat but I knew the bus would show up the minute I did. I had intended to eat in the restaurant, but for some reason the counter person handed me my meal in a bag to go. Since my usual table was occupied, I sighed and left; the entire day had been off like that. I should have known the universe had it in for me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Spark</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/09/2009-09-26-a-spark/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/09/2009-09-26-a-spark/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My eyes opened and this is what I saw. You can in yourself be anything you desire. You create yourself from a point. You define your own existence.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A soul defines itself.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What words cannot define, they can characterize, so that the truth may be recognized as it is encountered.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The existence of a soul is absolute, at once all and nothing.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The qualities of a soul are both infinite and eternal.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A soul is not a question, nor is a soul an answer.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A soul is a statement.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A soul is an expression, a unique, individual creation.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While I gazed in wonder, I realized that even before a soul embraces the awareness of other souls, the darkness of a soul embraces the light of other souls, filling the emptiness of its existence with the certainty of others, both as a foundation for its own reality, and a medium for the realization of its self.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Staring into the Face of Truth</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/07/2009-07-26-staring-into-the-face-of-truth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/07/2009-07-26-staring-into-the-face-of-truth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;A story is as good a way to organize your thoughts as anything else,&amp;rdquo; she points out, poised in the shadows in the doorway. I quickly conclude that she is playing the part of my conscience. That, or devil&amp;rsquo;s advocate. Either way, she&amp;rsquo;s me. I cannot say she does not really exist without implying the same of myself. She is in my mind, and of my mind, so I do not look at her. She cannot be seen, not in the flesh anyway, but it&amp;rsquo;s not like I have to look at her to see her. &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s been a long time since you&amp;rsquo;ve done this, though,&amp;rdquo; she observes, watching me carefully. I can tell there&amp;rsquo;s something on her mind. I can feel it. Technically, it&amp;rsquo;s on my mind, but I have long since learned that her thoughts are her own when she chooses to assert herself. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit like being in two places at the same time, a way to step outside my normal perspective and look at what I&amp;rsquo;ve become.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impulse</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/07/2009-07-25-impulse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/07/2009-07-25-impulse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Who am I? Why am I here? What is the point of my existence? These are questions we all ask at some point in our lives, and we can go our entire lives without knowing the answer. I suspect that a lot of people try to avoid thinking about it, not knowing how to begin answering, and I wonder how long a person can go without asking them. There are an endless number of situations and circumstances that can force us to confront these questions, and other soul searching questions like them. For me, the question can come up as a result of gender issues, but I&amp;rsquo;ve had it come up in many other circumstances. The answers, whatever they are, test the limits of my understanding, because in many ways I am the awareness brought into focus by both the sum and the gestalt of my understanding. In the scope of my understanding, I am aware that I am not driven by a desire to be female. I am driven by an impulse that is at once too simple and too complex for words, because words will never serve to express that impulse. Because I found myself in a body that I was not able to express myself properly in, it was only natural for me to become obsessed with finding a better way to express myself. I put a lot of thought and effort into figuring out the best way to embody myself in human terms, and because I was thinking in human terms, my self image is based on understanding the compromises that allowed me to be as true to myself as possible. Of course, human limitations are based on the limitations of reality, which are the perceived limits of existence &amp;ndash; or rather the limits of perception. The plain, simple and painful truth is that I am driven to do something that can not be done within those limits &amp;ndash; as we understand them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It Takes a Village to Break a Child</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/07/2009-07-24-it-takes-a-village-to-break-a-child/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/07/2009-07-24-it-takes-a-village-to-break-a-child/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I do not often get comments on my blog; if I exclude the pingbacks, spam and my own replies, I&amp;rsquo;ve received twenty-two comments from ten different individuals since I started the eye of paradox two years ago. Four of those people have identified themselves as transgendered, and like every transgendered person I&amp;rsquo;ve known, it has affected their lives as bad or worse than mine and I do not have to explain myself to them to be understood. For a long time, I&amp;rsquo;ve understood that this condition is difficult or even impossible for people who have not experienced it to comprehend. In order to live with normal people, the &amp;ldquo;cisgendered&amp;rdquo; if I use the term that&amp;rsquo;s come into use to describe those who identify with their birth sex, I&amp;rsquo;ve had to go to incredible lengths to comprehend and empathize with them. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried many, many times to find a way to describe what it feels like to live with this condition, hoping to make it easier for my family and friends to understand me. As I mentioned, I do not always like what comes out when I write on this topic, because it is a very intensely emotional issue and intensely emotional writing just encourages people to accuse me of being mellow-dramatic. I honestly expect most people to be driven away by the things I have written. Growing up, it did not take me long to learn how incredibly unsympathetic most people are about this issue. I was never asked to explain myself. With the exception of my adopted mother, who confronted me when I was six to ask if I wanted to be a girl, no one ever asked me why I acted like a girl. By the time she asked, I knew better than to admit it, since every other time someone noticed I was just slapped, spanked, or jerked around while being criticized for acting like a girl and being commanded to stop. That does not mean I was not asking myself why I acted like a girl. Even though the question was often on my mind, the only answer that ever rang true was the one that the facts denied.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Point Penetrating Points Overlapping</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/07/2009-07-22-point-penetrating-points-overlapping/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/07/2009-07-22-point-penetrating-points-overlapping/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A number of my posts, particularly the ones dealing with transgender issues in my life, have been written on a long, dark night of the soul. It can be difficult to come back and read what I&amp;rsquo;ve posted and resist the urge to delete what I&amp;rsquo;ve written, because of how dark they are. I have moments when I think, if ever a family member happened to read them, some of what I&amp;rsquo;ve written could really hurt them. That was never the intention, and yet, there is a ring of truth to the posts I am not able to deny. It is an unfortunate fact that I&amp;rsquo;ve been hurt a great deal by people who never meant me harm because of things neither I nor they had any control over. It is not their fault that efforts to encourage my growth and development as a son or brother caused me so much pain; they were simply responding to what they perceived me to be. Our current society is the end product of thousands of generations of people struggling through life trying to make sense out of it. If that resulted in the division of human traits into masculine and feminine, and if the cultivation of gender roles led to a society that could not understand that there was a difference between the things that make people who they are and the things that make them what they are, it is not possible to assign fault or blame to any specific group, let alone a given person. As much as it would have made a difference in my life to have been raised among people who were more perceptive, or in a society that was more accepting of individual differences, I would still have grown up with the more difficult problem of being a girl in a boy&amp;rsquo;s body.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exercise in Imagination</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/07/2009-07-11-exercise-in-imagination/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/07/2009-07-11-exercise-in-imagination/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just stumbled across a few things I wrote for a creative writing class I took this past spring to fulfill an elective requirement. One of the assignments involved writing a short story based on a work of art found online. I had no trouble thinking of one that sparked my imagination. The painting &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://kyena.deviantart.com/art/Summer-comes-30814005&#34;&gt;Summer Comes&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; by Kyena was posted on DeviantArt on March 24, 2006, receiving special notice on April 12, 2006 as a &amp;ldquo;Daily Deviation&amp;rdquo; or a featured artwork on the popular artists&amp;rsquo; community site.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matter and Movement in Four--or More--Dimensions</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/07/2009-07-08-matter-and-movement-in-four-or-more-dimensions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/07/2009-07-08-matter-and-movement-in-four-or-more-dimensions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;These days, it only takes a little curiosity, access to the Internet, and a bit of patience to find explanations of progressive spatial dimensions or examples of four dimensional geometry, such as the old favorite the hyper-square.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some of the things you will find use analogies like Flatland, or animations which is a way of using time and motion to reveal a higher dimensional object using a lower dimensional cross section.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hidden in Plain Sight</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/07/2009-07-07-hidden-in-plain-sight/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/07/2009-07-07-hidden-in-plain-sight/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On April 27, 2008 at 12:36 am, I began a post &amp;ndash; this post, actually &amp;ndash; but got no further than the title. I don&amp;rsquo;t know if that was because that title summed up my feelings so well that there was no point to writing any further about what was on my mind. Yesterday, those words came back to me at the conclusion of &lt;a href=&#34;http://eyeofparadox.com/2009/07/06/a-glimpse-into-the-eye-of-paradox/&#34;&gt;A Glimpse into the Eye of Paradox&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve always thought of the truth as something that is hidden in plain sight, and approached it as something that we take so much for granted we really don&amp;rsquo;t know what to do with it. One might as well say that the truth that can be put into words is not the truth. Communication is more a matter of interpretation, and there is no singularity to interpretation. The truth is out there, and every time we encounter it, we are seeing it from a limited point of view. When we come across it again from a different point of view, we still recognize it as the truth but it not only appears different, we ourselves understand it in a different context.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Glimpse into the Eye of Paradox</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/07/2009-07-06-a-glimpse-into-the-eye-of-paradox/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/07/2009-07-06-a-glimpse-into-the-eye-of-paradox/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On any given day, a small handful of people find their way to the eye of paradox. Some of them probably just glance at an article to see if it&amp;rsquo;s relevant to the search that brought them here. One or two might actually read something.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once in a blue moon, someone leaves a short comment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Taken all together, I do not see anything to indicate that my words mean much. Is that frustrating?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Price of Dreams</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/07/2009-07-03-the-price-of-dreams/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/07/2009-07-03-the-price-of-dreams/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We never remember the beginning,&amp;rdquo; she said quietly. &amp;ldquo;We pretend not to know why—but then that is one of our favorite tricks, isn&amp;rsquo;t it?&amp;rdquo; she glanced up at me, smiling at my confused silence. With her arms crossed she began to drift about the room, examining objects while continuing this strange introduction. &amp;ldquo;We pretend not to know many things. We can even pretend not to know the truth. The horrible truth. But the beginning?&amp;rdquo; she paused and met my eye in the mirror. &amp;ldquo;Well there is an explanation for that one. We never remember the beginning because there never was a beginning. That&amp;rsquo;s one of those horrible parts of the truth we choose to miss.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Awakening</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/06/2009-06-30-111/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/06/2009-06-30-111/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have pointed out before that my struggle with gender dysphoria prompted me to search in all directions for a solution to being born in the wrong body, and the determination with which I pursued that goal in spite of all doubts and discouragements &amp;ndash; even attempts to accept things the way they were, adapting to and adopting the identity imposed on me by circumstances &amp;ndash; says a lot about me, and even about what I ultimately concluded. My existence may be supported by reality, the physical, chemical, biological and sociological fabric out of which we all seem to be spun, but none of these things are me. I exist in my mind and that is why the way I perceive myself in my own mind can not only contradict my physical form, but trump it in importance to my survival. I have heard the theories and arguments on nature versus nurture and taking my own experience into consideration I can say that there are elements in both that can help shape who you are, but only by presenting the options or stimulus necessary for you to determine who you are. I cannot tell you if this is a process of creation or revelation; it feels like both. I am the driving and defining force within my own mind; my mind is the structure and articulation of my soul.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Slightly Left of Nowhere</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/06/2009-06-28-slightly-left-of-nowhere/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/06/2009-06-28-slightly-left-of-nowhere/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I rarely have time to write or draw, and as my friend keeps reminding me, I&amp;rsquo;ve little hope making a living as an artist or writer. I have to agree, knowing that even brilliant writing and art takes a massive investment of time and effort up front. That seems to be a recurring theme in my life, however. I have never really had the things I needed to succeed in life. I have almost always had a reasonable substitute for the things I lack, which I am sure could have been used to achieve success, if success meant anything in the absence of a life worth living. The hard, cold facts of life undermine my identity and force me to live the life of a person that does not exist. I succeeded in earning enough to live and function as a man, but the process left me with no sense of myself as a person; nothing that I did felt real to me and nothing that I engaged in felt meaningful.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It is Where You Can, and Yet... CAN You? On Writing What I Know.</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/06/2009-06-26-it-is-where-you-can-and-yet-can-you-on-writing-what-i-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/06/2009-06-26-it-is-where-you-can-and-yet-can-you-on-writing-what-i-know/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I may have commented on it in passing, and it is something I certainly never miss, but my art and writing have always brought out the real me. In a sense, that is appropriate enough; isn&amp;rsquo;t it a common recommendation that writers draw from their own experiences? I often feel that my escape into fantasy or science fiction has been good for my sanity, but bad for my hopes of a writing career. I could be wrong. I see enough gender bending in books, manga and film. I find it interesting that most cases involve a boy turned into a girl against his will. Interestingly enough, the first time I picked up an issue of Ranma 1/2, I put it back when I discovered that Ranma considered his ability to become a girl a curse. I did not think I could stomach reading about a guy hated having what I so desperately longed for. Months later, I gave Ranma 1/2 a second chance and eventually came to like him and appreciate what he was going through. I became a fan, read all the manga, watched as much of the anime as I could stand (if you&amp;rsquo;ve tried, you know why I say that), and even wrote over a million words of fan fiction. I&amp;rsquo;m still trying to complete volume five; it&amp;rsquo;s hard to give it my attention when I am struggling to hold myself together and it&amp;rsquo;s writing that doesn&amp;rsquo;t pay.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recapitulation &amp;amp; Reflection</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/06/2009-06-25-recapitulation-reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/06/2009-06-25-recapitulation-reflection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A person looking at my blog might get the impression that I do not get much writing done, and it is true that there are a lot of things in my life that get in the way of me writing most of the things I want to. The inside dope is that much of what I do write, I am not sure I want to share. Does anyone not afflicted with gender dysphoria even care about transgender issues? I honestly do not know. I&amp;rsquo;ve known people who were sympathetic, curious, interested, confused, upset and even terrified by the topic. It is an uncomfortable topic, and I do not blame people for not wanting to talk about it; and if no one wants to talk about it (except those of us who have to live with it) why would anyone want to read about it? I dunno, but I do have a lot to say about it, and sometimes I do not realize how much until the words start to spill out. Once they do, I begin to find clarity and focus. It helps me to write it, it helps me to come back and read it, and it has a place here in my blog, because it deals with the paradox of my life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Absolute Truth</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/10/2008-10-03-the-absolute-truth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/10/2008-10-03-the-absolute-truth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The best representation of a thing is the thing itself and yet there are things that we experience great difficulty recognizing in their true form.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The truth is one of those things.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In speaking of the truth, what we have is a word&amp;ndash;and as a representation of a thing, a word provides a label for a concept that is meaningless without an accurate understanding of what the concept represents.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Understanding the true meaning of truth is a challenge because it calls upon itself for validation, which is a logical fallacy. Or is it?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fly By - Asteroids</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/09/2008-09-30-fly-by-asteroids/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/09/2008-09-30-fly-by-asteroids/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/a-aism-space-art-fly-by-0505081.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Fly By&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once again, I am posting images from my space art portfolio. This is a reworking of one of the first space art cover illustrations I attempted, but never submitted, for Analog. It was created in Photoshop as part of a new series of space art conceived as &amp;ldquo;variations on a theme&amp;rdquo; using similar elements in different ways. In keeping with the role of a concept artist, this series is supposed to demonstrate an ability to create a number of detailed proof images quickly, so each image in this series was produced in an evening or afternoon. The fact that the images all share a common origin and elements also gives them a kind of storyboard quality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Divide by Zero</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/09/2008-09-18-divide-by-zero/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/09/2008-09-18-divide-by-zero/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Is it possible to divide a number by zero? Conventional thinking in mathematics declares this to be impossible, but this answer is contingent on a point of view. The problem here lies in the normal interpretation of the value of the number zero; a representation of &amp;ldquo;nothing&amp;rdquo; zero is seen as more of a place holder, a number that has no value. By contrast, infinity is a value that has no number. In multiplication, the value of any number times zero is zero. It is like declaring a number in theory. It is like saying &amp;ldquo;no number&amp;rdquo; and when it comes to division by zero, one might as well be saying &amp;ldquo;no division&amp;rdquo; because use of the number zero declares no number of parts into which a value could be separated, including one, producing a value in no parts. The common assumption is that division by zero would equal infinity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blue Horizon</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/09/2008-09-17-blue-horizon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/09/2008-09-17-blue-horizon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://eyeofparadox.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/09/20070414-blue-horizon-640x900-20090414-1324-00.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/20070414-blue-horizon-640x900-20090414-1324-00.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once more, I thought it would be nice to add a little visual content to the eye of paradox by posting one of the images from my voidscape collection of space art. This is actually a pre-visualization done at a smaller scale than I normally work in Photoshop, using small Terragen renders, to help with a work in progress. To those familiar with my Art is Murder gallery as Alexandrea V. Morgan, the planets first appeared on a wallpaper graphic titled &amp;ldquo;Artemis and Athena&amp;rdquo; which was a sneak-preview of the the project I was working on. However, this piece uses the planets in the same orientation they were originally developed, rather than the vertical composition I posted on Art is Murder, to try to keep the lighting of the planets somewhat consistent with the lighting of the terrain.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gravity in a Distributed, Process Driven, Information-Based Universe</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/09/2008-09-17-gravity-in-a-distributed-process-driven-information-based-universe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/09/2008-09-17-gravity-in-a-distributed-process-driven-information-based-universe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To a curious mind, gravity is a curious phenomenon. The more one pays attention to it, the more fascinating and mysterious it becomes. Today, we have the advantage of having had great minds ponder the mystery and define what can be observed and inferred by studying it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Newton pondered the question &amp;ldquo;why do objects fall?&amp;rdquo; and provided us with a theory of universal gravity (along with his three laws of motion). He essentially defined the terms we now use to describe and quantify gravity, the force that attracts objects with mass to each other.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Above the Horizon</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/07/2008-07-17-above-the-horizon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/07/2008-07-17-above-the-horizon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://eyeofparadox.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/09/a-aism-xscape.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/a-aism-xscape.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Above the Horizon&#34; title=&#34;a-aism-xscape&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is my first attempt to feature some of my artwork here on the eye of paradox. I have always had a strong interest in becoming a professional artist, in spite of having little time and insufficient resources to develop my skills to that level. I started out with the right intentions, pursuing an art degree, but the path I started on led down a different and darker route. I never gave up on the idea, even though it&amp;rsquo;s taken a long time to get to where I am now as an artist and a writer. In the hopes of breaking into publication creating science fiction themed cover art, I became interested in creating voidscapes, images set in outer space. I have learned enough by now to know how much more I have to learn to achieve that goal. I have continued to improve with each work, and I will post some of my more recent efforts or even works in progress as the whim strikes me. Of course, if I get some kind of response to my efforts, the whim might strike more frequently.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Damage is Done</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/05/2008-05-15-the-damage-is-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/05/2008-05-15-the-damage-is-done/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wonder what is going to happen next. I wonder if I can hold it together to get a job and move out on my own. I wonder if I can manage to hold on to that job and support myself. I wonder, because I am not really wanted where I am. The only support I can count on, the support of my family and friends, is conditional. It always has been. It has always been conditional on me finding a way to get steady on my own two feet. The irony of that always brings a smile of agony. I know what they want, and that they want it for me, for me to become independent. It is something I do want. The problem is that it leaves me alone inside a life that holds absolutely no meaning for me. This person that I pretend to be, because he means something to his friends and family, means nothing to me. He does not mean enough, to the people who employ him, to have any purpose. He can be replaced by anyone and cannot compete with the living.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A True Identity is Nothing to Fear</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/05/2008-05-14-a-true-identity-is-nothing-to-fear/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/05/2008-05-14-a-true-identity-is-nothing-to-fear/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The response I received to my last post, &lt;a href=&#34;http://eyeofparadox.com/2008/05/11/conundrum/&#34;&gt;Conundrum&lt;/a&gt;, prompted me to check out the recent posts of the people who commented or posted blogs in the transgender category yesterday. As a result, I became aware of the outcry against the appointment of Dr. Kenneth Zucker, Dr. Ray Blanchard, and J. Michael Bailey, by the American Psychiatric Association (APA), to the work group responsible for revising the entry for Gender Identity Disorder (GID) in the Manual for Diagnosis of Mental Disorders. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://genderoutlaw.wordpress.com/2008/05/11/the-apa-appointment-of-zucker-et-al-and-gender-variant-children/&#34;&gt;first blog&lt;/a&gt; I read on the subject, posted by Gender Outlaw, struck a very personal chord with me. In addition to being transgendered, I was put up for adoption when I was four and spent a year in foster care while the state attempted to contact my biological father so that he might claim his custody rights. It was during my time in foster care that I was terrorized out of identifying myself as a girl and learned to keep my true identity a secret. It took time to learn how to restrain my natural impulses and act like a boy, and the threat of abandonment and rejection was used to reinforce &amp;ldquo;correct&amp;rdquo; behavior. By the time I was adopted, this conditioning had scarred me for life, rendering me incapable of trusting anyone with my true thoughts and feelings. When my new family noticed my feminine traits and confronted me with questions about my behavior, or offered even a mild rebuke for &amp;ldquo;acting like a girl&amp;rdquo; I was consumed with that fear of rejection and lied to deflect any suspicions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conundrum</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/05/2008-05-12-conundrum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/05/2008-05-12-conundrum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I find myself puzzling over the weird fact of my existence. The Internet created an opportunity to show a side of myself that I had long kept hidden.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am, at least in the terms used by the medical community (and by extension, the LGBTQ community), transgendered; in spite of being born and raised male the core of my identity is female.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is not a convenient or desirable situation, and it puts me in constant conflict between who I am and what I am.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is the Point?</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/03/2008-03-01-what-is-the-point/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/03/2008-03-01-what-is-the-point/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am back in school, freshly enrolled in the University of Phoenix in pursuit of a Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s Degree in Information Technology&amp;ndash;Visual Communications. I do not have a great deal of time outside of work to devote to this, so I was naturally put out when the site went down in the middle of a post. Not just any post, but a post in which I found myself inspired to posit a somewhat challenging question. Of course that post is now forever lost, inspiring this wonderful missive. When you strive to do not only what is required of you, when you strive to do more than is expected of you and stumble into a thought or question that has real potential, only to have that effort vanish without a trace, does it not make you wonder if there is any point?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Point Paradox</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/02/2008-02-23-point-paradox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/02/2008-02-23-point-paradox/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“Detailing the dynamics of point paradox has never been easy, but the founding principle is prime awareness, the awareness of one, all and none&amp;quot; she elaborated, settling lightly on the arm of the couch.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Point paradox is initially a question of absolutes. An absolute can be represented with a value of ‘one’, ‘zero’ and ‘infinite’. These values are all essentially equal, depending on perspective.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The evolution of the soul begins with the exploration of this prime awareness, which is initially the struggle of one to comprehend the duality of all and none.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Medium of Existence</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/02/2008-02-23-the-medium-of-existence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/02/2008-02-23-the-medium-of-existence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“A soul is absolute and absolutes are autonomous,” she asserted firmly. “A mind is paradoxical, acting as an inclusive, exclusive and occlusive interface between absolutes, abstractions and manifestations. A mind, with the absolute of a soul as its foundation, is the focus of existence, whether real, surreal or ideal. In short, the mind is the medium of existence, and a single mind can coordinate the disposition of the absolute, the absolutes, and any distillation derived there from.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m not dead yet...</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/02/2008-02-21-im-not-dead-yet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/02/2008-02-21-im-not-dead-yet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The rare and occasional visitor to the eye of paradox will note that I have been absent for the most part from my own blog. Ironically, this is not because I have nothing to say. Quite the opposite; I have too much to say and too little time to spend on writing any of it down. That is my reward for trying to improve my education and hold down a steady job. It underscores the problem of trying to do what is expected of you. I am expected to find my place in the world in spite of the fact that there is no place for me in this world. If you broke me up into bits and pieces, there is some place in the world for each of those parts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Mind Races On While the Pen Drags Behind</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/2007-08-31-the-mind-races-on-while-the-pen-drags-behind/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/2007-08-31-the-mind-races-on-while-the-pen-drags-behind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My previous post on &lt;em&gt;The Paradox of Death&lt;/em&gt; is a bit more stream of consciousness than I had intended. That is one of the things that happens when writing about thinking existentially. I know I am going to have to reassess what I wrote; there are a lot of good thoughts in there, but I&amp;rsquo;m not surprised if people find it difficult to read. I had an idea and just could not hold it in a firm grasp, so the result is a bit of a train-wreck.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Paradox of Death</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/2007-08-24-the-paradox-of-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/2007-08-24-the-paradox-of-death/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is more to this, to existing, than meets the eye. It is its own prerequisite and it hurts think about why or how. The only thing that hurts more is trying to make sense &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; existing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But, given our circumstances, we can&amp;rsquo;t really afford to take it for granted. By a certain age, we know that death awaits, but what does it really mean, in practice?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Its not a box you can just think you way out of, but its always safe to assume there is no valid alternative to &lt;em&gt;being.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Social Stratification</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/2007-08-22-the-impact-of-social-stratification/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/2007-08-22-the-impact-of-social-stratification/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re all human. None of us have a say in what circumstances we are born. Pretty much any other characteristic by which people can be defined produces some form of social stratification.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thinking about it boggles the mind.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve grown up with the ideas of caste and class, and tried to understand how anyone can willingly accept being &amp;ldquo;put in their place&amp;rdquo; by the people around them. In the end, I think it all comes down to the perception of power, the ways in which circumstances can be used to dominate society.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Still Scratching That Itch</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/2007-08-16-still-scratching-that-itch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/2007-08-16-still-scratching-that-itch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The whole moving and searching for a better job thing is going slowly, so even with school work, there&amp;rsquo;s been time to write. Maybe I should not say, write, precisely. I have had a bit of time to pound out some new ideas and wrestle with some old ones, and I am coming to an agreement with myself about what I wanted to write, what I actually wrote, and what I hope to get written. I&amp;rsquo;ve actually been working on a group of related stories based on a common inspiration for years, so there is more material for me to draw from than the seven chapters I&amp;rsquo;ve posted.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Touch of Fear</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/2007-08-13-a-touch-of-fear/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/2007-08-13-a-touch-of-fear/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A good scare is like good sex. It is gripping and all consuming for an eternal moment, but once it has washed through you and you catch your breath, it evaporates. Like smoke, it unravels, curling in upon itself and expanding into nothing. Before you know it, only the memory remains.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paying the Price</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/2007-08-13-paying-the-price/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/2007-08-13-paying-the-price/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As true as it is that some people are incapable of valuing things they have not paid the price for, the fact is that free money is never free. There is terrible cost for being on the public dole, that is immediately evident when you walk into a welfare community.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Being on public assistance or living on a reservation, the cost of that free income or housing is having to live in poverty. It provides just enough to survive but not enough to advance. While many assistance programs include job training and placement programs, the jobs one can qualify for rarely provide better incomes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take a Moment to Reflect</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/2007-08-13-take-a-moment-to-reflect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/2007-08-13-take-a-moment-to-reflect/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Even with the best intentions no one has the right to impose a system of thought or action on anyone against their will. Ironically, that is exactly what has happened to all of us as we were born into this world.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is in some ways no different than being born into slavery, in the sense that we come into the world having no say in the system that will govern our lives, and we spend our most vulnerable years being programmed to become obedient citizens and uphold the status quo.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Best Way to Fit In? Don&#39;t Stand Out</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/2007-08-13-the-best-way-to-fit-in-dont-stand-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/2007-08-13-the-best-way-to-fit-in-dont-stand-out/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Grouping is an activity that comes instinctively and automatically to people. It is part of a filtering process that allows us to make sense of our universe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anything can serve as criteria for grouping, but because this is a perceptual-interpretive process; differences and similarities in physical characteristics are the most prevalent. As we learn and grow, we also associate ideas and experiences with the items in our cognitive inventory.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We give values to people, places and things based on personal experience, inherited attitudes and beliefs, and assumptions. Part of our ability to form instant impressions and make immediate judgments is based upon preconception&amp;ndash;ideas we have formed previously.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Being at Odds with Life</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/2007-08-09-being-at-odds-with-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/2007-08-09-being-at-odds-with-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I never imagined that I had a monopoly on being at odds with life. It is simply a state of being with which I am much too familiar. I have spent most of my life struggling with things that most people take for granted, stumbling and falling in places where most people stride with confidence and conviction. Strangely, I can dance through other places where most people crawl along blindly in fear and confusion or turn and run from in terror. I am not like everyone else, and I can not just be like everyone else and do what everyone else does. In order to live like other people, I have to learn the role and act the part &amp;ndash; but the performance I put on never ends and by going through the motions I end up not having a life of my own.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open Letter to Lindsay Lohan</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/2007-08-09-open-letter-to-lindsay-lohan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/2007-08-09-open-letter-to-lindsay-lohan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello, Lindsay. I don&amp;rsquo;t know you and you certainly do not know me! That said, I do not really expect you to actually read this letter, and if you do, I really do not expect anything from you. Still, it is an open letter &lt;em&gt;for&lt;/em&gt; you, and regardless of who else reads it, it is meant only for &lt;em&gt;you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t have a very clear idea why I am doing this, and if anything actually comes of it, I will probably regret it at some point. I&amp;rsquo;m not even sure how to begin. I am not your friend. I am not even asking to be your friend &amp;ndash; I don&amp;rsquo;t want anything &lt;em&gt;from&lt;/em&gt; you. I appreciate what you have done in your life as an artist more than enough. I do have a kind of selfish interest in you, and honestly it&amp;rsquo;s weird enough to scare you if it is looked at in a certain way. So, I&amp;rsquo;ll run the risk of weirding you out right up front: I probably would have liked being you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Price of Admission</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/2007-08-06-the-price-of-admission/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/2007-08-06-the-price-of-admission/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What is a society, what is it made up of and how does it work? The simple answer is, jobs. Society is all about jobs. Living in the wild, surviving on their own, human beings had no jobs. Their lives were defined by the tasks that needed to be done in order to be able to survive.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A bunch of people living together and sharing their resources does a better job of surviving, and each person becomes primarily responsible for the task he or she is best suited to do.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Time in a Distributed, Process Driven, Information-Based Universe</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/07/2007-07-30-time-in-a-distributed-process-driven-information-based-universe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/07/2007-07-30-time-in-a-distributed-process-driven-information-based-universe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In order to understand time it becomes necessary to ask if time is an objective or subjective medium. To be clear, by considering time subjectively I do not mean simply in terms of our subjective perception of time. The question asks if time is absolute, and thus events at different points in time persist in their own frame of reference with a constant relative position in time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Basically, it asks if there are actual positions in and structure to time. The alternative, subjective time, deals with the concept of time as being functional, an operation upon the objective structure of matter and energy in space like the constant balancing of an equation in which there is no actual time, just a present state of the equation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>That Itch to Write</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/07/2007-07-29-that-itch-to-write/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/07/2007-07-29-that-itch-to-write/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It seems that the itch to start working on a book has come back to me. It has to be an insane impulse, because with school and work I have no idea where I&amp;rsquo;ll find time to actually write anything. Then there&amp;rsquo;s the fact that I&amp;rsquo;ll be moving in the next few weeks and looking for a new job. I know I must be crazy. Of course, that&amp;rsquo;s not a new feeling for me!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is evil?</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/07/2007-07-25-what-is-evil/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/07/2007-07-25-what-is-evil/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is a line in &amp;ldquo;The Matrix&amp;rdquo; when Morpheus confronts Neo about a wrongness in the world, &amp;ldquo;like a splinter in your mind.&amp;rdquo;  It was caused by an instinctive apprehension of the artificial reality he was trapped in.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is similar to a feeling many people have about our own reality. There is a wrongness in the world, evident in the mystery of life, the inevitability of death and in the things that we call evil.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GID?</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/07/2007-07-20-gid/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/07/2007-07-20-gid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my bio on Helium, I confided a history of GID. That is Gender Identity Disorder, for those of you who did not know. There are a number of problems with that particular label for a condition that is poorly understood at best and entirely subjective at worst. Other terms that can be used are Gender Dysphoria or Transgendered, and like GID, there are issues inherent in their use as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Explaining the Different Dimensions</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/07/2007-07-18-explaining-the-different-dimensions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/07/2007-07-18-explaining-the-different-dimensions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I normally avoid the first person when writing an article or essay, but in this case I need to begin with a personal story&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A year into my studies at Humboldt State University a mutual acquaintance showed up at my friend&amp;rsquo;s apartment while I was visiting and regaled us with his synopsis of a lecture on dimensions he recently attended.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I do not recall what the class was, and I&amp;rsquo;m not even sure I remember the student&amp;rsquo;s name, but I will never forget that conversation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Helium.com Articles</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/07/2007-07-18-heliumcom-articles/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/07/2007-07-18-heliumcom-articles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been scratching out ideas since the writing bug first bit me in grade school. Somewhere in the back of my mind I always had this notion that I was going to devote some part of my life to writing. Of course, I&amp;rsquo;ve spent much more time thinking, while trying to &lt;em&gt;find&lt;/em&gt; time to get anything written! Inevitably, when the time came to start writing, I had thoughts waiting to be expressed. I used to just spill them out in a notepad and file them away, but having tripped over a link to Helium a few months ago (AN: this was back in 2007; the site is long gone now), I found a more interesting place to put them. After publishing my tenth article, I got an itch for something more. I wanted to be able to continue to explore the ideas that bit me, and that really calls for something more like a blog. So, even though I will (or at least intended to, at the time) continue to publish articles on Helium, I am also going to be exploring some of them here in more detail.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is there really such a thing as the present?</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/07/2007-07-18-is-there-really-such-a-thing-as-the-present/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/07/2007-07-18-is-there-really-such-a-thing-as-the-present/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Is there really such a thing as time? That is a question it is helpful to ask in order to address what we call the present. That is because our experience of time is completely subjective and because everything we are is dependent on that peculiar subjectivity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Time is what we derive from the ceaseless transformation that is part of awareness, consciousness, thought, perception, action and reaction.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Time is our measure of the dynamic quality of existence that compliments the static quality of existence the latter of which allows the world and ourselves to be manifest.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Noosphere: The Future of Evolution?</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/07/2007-07-18-noosphere-the-future-of-evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/07/2007-07-18-noosphere-the-future-of-evolution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Those moments in life when we are confronted with a new concept or idea can be life altering, seemingly setting the mind free to roam a new and undiscovered country or even knocking the world completely off its hinges.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes that can happen even with just a new word or concept for something we&amp;rsquo;ve had an inkling of all along.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In some cases, it is more like getting hit in the head with a brick and realizing that this strange and wonderous idea has been staring us in the face for so long we have actually gotten in the habit of ignoring it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Readers from Helium</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/07/2007-07-18-readers-from-helium/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/07/2007-07-18-readers-from-helium/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Among the features not provided for contributors on the now-defunct Helium writer&amp;rsquo;s website was a way for readers to respond directly to the writers. While it was active, the only way for readers to respond on Helium was by posting their own thoughts on the topic at hand. Those who were so inclined were welcome to do so, there, but I imagined that not all responses would have been suited to that approach, so I invited my readers to respond here if they preferred.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Implications of the Mind in Matter: The Prospect of Oblivion</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/07/2007-07-18-the-implications-of-the-mind-in-matter-the-prospect-of-oblivion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/07/2007-07-18-the-implications-of-the-mind-in-matter-the-prospect-of-oblivion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Posted on Helium under: &lt;strong&gt;The fundamentals of self-awareness&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The mind is an inherently fascinating and difficult subject to pin down. Philosophers have been musing over the mysteries of the mind for thousands of years but it is, without doubt, the scientists who find it the most frustrating to study.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The subjective nature of the mind makes it ill suited for scientific scrutiny, but scientists have found ways to pursue the matter indirectly. While some scientists have probed the frontier of the mind through behavioral psychology, others have focused their attention on the body and the brain.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Purpose of Religion</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/07/2007-07-18-the-purpose-of-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/07/2007-07-18-the-purpose-of-religion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In asking about the purpose of religion, it is necessary to ask first if religion is not simply a product of our own search for purpose?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The answer to the primary question depends on whether we perceive religion as having a divine origin or if we see it as the origin of divine thinking.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Either way, religion comes to us through human agents, so we have to begin by looking at what it is to be human.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
