<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Awareness on eyeofparadox.com [eyeofparadox.wordpress.com] to eyeofparadox.github.io</title>
    <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/categories/awareness/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Awareness on eyeofparadox.com [eyeofparadox.wordpress.com] to eyeofparadox.github.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://eyeofparadox.github.io/categories/awareness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Musings On Physics &amp;amp; Metaphysics</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2018/09/2018-09-16-musings-on-physics-metaphysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2018/09/2018-09-16-musings-on-physics-metaphysics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A lot of time has passed since I had the impulse to post anything; that does not mean I stopped writing my thoughts down! I came across the following on a buried tab in my Notepad++ application. I have tons of random notes like this, and often do nothing with them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I mean, they&amp;rsquo;re not really intended for the average reader. You might not be able to follow them, and I don&amp;rsquo;t really know what parts need further elaboration for you to grok them. Even so, I can still throw them out there and hope that you will comment or request explanations if you need them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Spark</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/09/2009-09-26-a-spark/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/09/2009-09-26-a-spark/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My eyes opened and this is what I saw. You can in yourself be anything you desire. You create yourself from a point. You define your own existence.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A soul defines itself.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What words cannot define, they can characterize, so that the truth may be recognized as it is encountered.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The existence of a soul is absolute, at once all and nothing.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The qualities of a soul are both infinite and eternal.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A soul is not a question, nor is a soul an answer.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A soul is a statement.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A soul is an expression, a unique, individual creation.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While I gazed in wonder, I realized that even before a soul embraces the awareness of other souls, the darkness of a soul embraces the light of other souls, filling the emptiness of its existence with the certainty of others, both as a foundation for its own reality, and a medium for the realization of its self.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
