<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fair-Play on eyeofparadox.com [eyeofparadox.wordpress.com] to eyeofparadox.github.io</title>
    <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/categories/fair-play/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fair-Play on eyeofparadox.com [eyeofparadox.wordpress.com] to eyeofparadox.github.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://eyeofparadox.github.io/categories/fair-play/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fair and Sound: DegreeStory Replies</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2016/08/2016-08-25-fair-and-sound-degreestory-replies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2016/08/2016-08-25-fair-and-sound-degreestory-replies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Original publication: December 7, 2013&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Re: University of Phoenix Online&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Associate of Arts in Business&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bachelor of Science in Information Technology for Visual Communications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;article-1---100-words-answering-the-question&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Article #1 - 100 words answering the question:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;is-your-pay-fair&#34;&gt;Is your pay fair?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;fair-but-not-very-fair&#34;&gt;Fair, But Not &lt;em&gt;Very&lt;/em&gt; Fair&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are dozens of great lines in “The Princess Bride” like “Never go up against a Sicilian when Death is on the line” or “Hello! My name is Inigo Montoya. You killed my father. Prepare to die.” The one that holds the most truth, however, is, “Life isn’t fair, Princess. Anyone who says otherwise is trying to sell something.” What is true about life is true about work. I have never objected to working for a living, but as often as not I’ve found myself in a situation where I was living only to work. I’m an artist and a writer, so I am constantly driven to create—but I’ve rarely been lucky enough to get paid for my art or writing. So, I usually had a full time job, or two or three part time or contract jobs just to pay the bills. I would spend eight hours at work, as much as 3 hours communing to and from work, and another eight hours working on projects at home. I would get a few hours of sleep, and do it all again the next day, squeezing meals in when I had half an hour to spare.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It Takes a Village to Break a Child</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/07/2009-07-24-it-takes-a-village-to-break-a-child/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/07/2009-07-24-it-takes-a-village-to-break-a-child/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I do not often get comments on my blog; if I exclude the pingbacks, spam and my own replies, I&amp;rsquo;ve received twenty-two comments from ten different individuals since I started the eye of paradox two years ago. Four of those people have identified themselves as transgendered, and like every transgendered person I&amp;rsquo;ve known, it has affected their lives as bad or worse than mine and I do not have to explain myself to them to be understood. For a long time, I&amp;rsquo;ve understood that this condition is difficult or even impossible for people who have not experienced it to comprehend. In order to live with normal people, the &amp;ldquo;cisgendered&amp;rdquo; if I use the term that&amp;rsquo;s come into use to describe those who identify with their birth sex, I&amp;rsquo;ve had to go to incredible lengths to comprehend and empathize with them. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried many, many times to find a way to describe what it feels like to live with this condition, hoping to make it easier for my family and friends to understand me. As I mentioned, I do not always like what comes out when I write on this topic, because it is a very intensely emotional issue and intensely emotional writing just encourages people to accuse me of being mellow-dramatic. I honestly expect most people to be driven away by the things I have written. Growing up, it did not take me long to learn how incredibly unsympathetic most people are about this issue. I was never asked to explain myself. With the exception of my adopted mother, who confronted me when I was six to ask if I wanted to be a girl, no one ever asked me why I acted like a girl. By the time she asked, I knew better than to admit it, since every other time someone noticed I was just slapped, spanked, or jerked around while being criticized for acting like a girl and being commanded to stop. That does not mean I was not asking myself why I acted like a girl. Even though the question was often on my mind, the only answer that ever rang true was the one that the facts denied.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Point Penetrating Points Overlapping</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/07/2009-07-22-point-penetrating-points-overlapping/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/07/2009-07-22-point-penetrating-points-overlapping/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A number of my posts, particularly the ones dealing with transgender issues in my life, have been written on a long, dark night of the soul. It can be difficult to come back and read what I&amp;rsquo;ve posted and resist the urge to delete what I&amp;rsquo;ve written, because of how dark they are. I have moments when I think, if ever a family member happened to read them, some of what I&amp;rsquo;ve written could really hurt them. That was never the intention, and yet, there is a ring of truth to the posts I am not able to deny. It is an unfortunate fact that I&amp;rsquo;ve been hurt a great deal by people who never meant me harm because of things neither I nor they had any control over. It is not their fault that efforts to encourage my growth and development as a son or brother caused me so much pain; they were simply responding to what they perceived me to be. Our current society is the end product of thousands of generations of people struggling through life trying to make sense out of it. If that resulted in the division of human traits into masculine and feminine, and if the cultivation of gender roles led to a society that could not understand that there was a difference between the things that make people who they are and the things that make them what they are, it is not possible to assign fault or blame to any specific group, let alone a given person. As much as it would have made a difference in my life to have been raised among people who were more perceptive, or in a society that was more accepting of individual differences, I would still have grown up with the more difficult problem of being a girl in a boy&amp;rsquo;s body.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Slightly Left of Nowhere</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/06/2009-06-28-slightly-left-of-nowhere/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/06/2009-06-28-slightly-left-of-nowhere/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I rarely have time to write or draw, and as my friend keeps reminding me, I&amp;rsquo;ve little hope making a living as an artist or writer. I have to agree, knowing that even brilliant writing and art takes a massive investment of time and effort up front. That seems to be a recurring theme in my life, however. I have never really had the things I needed to succeed in life. I have almost always had a reasonable substitute for the things I lack, which I am sure could have been used to achieve success, if success meant anything in the absence of a life worth living. The hard, cold facts of life undermine my identity and force me to live the life of a person that does not exist. I succeeded in earning enough to live and function as a man, but the process left me with no sense of myself as a person; nothing that I did felt real to me and nothing that I engaged in felt meaningful.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Damage is Done</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/05/2008-05-15-the-damage-is-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/05/2008-05-15-the-damage-is-done/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wonder what is going to happen next. I wonder if I can hold it together to get a job and move out on my own. I wonder if I can manage to hold on to that job and support myself. I wonder, because I am not really wanted where I am. The only support I can count on, the support of my family and friends, is conditional. It always has been. It has always been conditional on me finding a way to get steady on my own two feet. The irony of that always brings a smile of agony. I know what they want, and that they want it for me, for me to become independent. It is something I do want. The problem is that it leaves me alone inside a life that holds absolutely no meaning for me. This person that I pretend to be, because he means something to his friends and family, means nothing to me. He does not mean enough, to the people who employ him, to have any purpose. He can be replaced by anyone and cannot compete with the living.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A True Identity is Nothing to Fear</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/05/2008-05-14-a-true-identity-is-nothing-to-fear/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/05/2008-05-14-a-true-identity-is-nothing-to-fear/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The response I received to my last post, &lt;a href=&#34;http://eyeofparadox.com/2008/05/11/conundrum/&#34;&gt;Conundrum&lt;/a&gt;, prompted me to check out the recent posts of the people who commented or posted blogs in the transgender category yesterday. As a result, I became aware of the outcry against the appointment of Dr. Kenneth Zucker, Dr. Ray Blanchard, and J. Michael Bailey, by the American Psychiatric Association (APA), to the work group responsible for revising the entry for Gender Identity Disorder (GID) in the Manual for Diagnosis of Mental Disorders. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://genderoutlaw.wordpress.com/2008/05/11/the-apa-appointment-of-zucker-et-al-and-gender-variant-children/&#34;&gt;first blog&lt;/a&gt; I read on the subject, posted by Gender Outlaw, struck a very personal chord with me. In addition to being transgendered, I was put up for adoption when I was four and spent a year in foster care while the state attempted to contact my biological father so that he might claim his custody rights. It was during my time in foster care that I was terrorized out of identifying myself as a girl and learned to keep my true identity a secret. It took time to learn how to restrain my natural impulses and act like a boy, and the threat of abandonment and rejection was used to reinforce &amp;ldquo;correct&amp;rdquo; behavior. By the time I was adopted, this conditioning had scarred me for life, rendering me incapable of trusting anyone with my true thoughts and feelings. When my new family noticed my feminine traits and confronted me with questions about my behavior, or offered even a mild rebuke for &amp;ldquo;acting like a girl&amp;rdquo; I was consumed with that fear of rejection and lied to deflect any suspicions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conundrum</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/05/2008-05-12-conundrum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/05/2008-05-12-conundrum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I find myself puzzling over the weird fact of my existence. The Internet created an opportunity to show a side of myself that I had long kept hidden.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am, at least in the terms used by the medical community (and by extension, the LGBTQ community), transgendered; in spite of being born and raised male the core of my identity is female.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is not a convenient or desirable situation, and it puts me in constant conflict between who I am and what I am.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Social Stratification</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/2007-08-22-the-impact-of-social-stratification/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/2007-08-22-the-impact-of-social-stratification/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re all human. None of us have a say in what circumstances we are born. Pretty much any other characteristic by which people can be defined produces some form of social stratification.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thinking about it boggles the mind.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve grown up with the ideas of caste and class, and tried to understand how anyone can willingly accept being &amp;ldquo;put in their place&amp;rdquo; by the people around them. In the end, I think it all comes down to the perception of power, the ways in which circumstances can be used to dominate society.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paying the Price</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/2007-08-13-paying-the-price/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/2007-08-13-paying-the-price/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As true as it is that some people are incapable of valuing things they have not paid the price for, the fact is that free money is never free. There is terrible cost for being on the public dole, that is immediately evident when you walk into a welfare community.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Being on public assistance or living on a reservation, the cost of that free income or housing is having to live in poverty. It provides just enough to survive but not enough to advance. While many assistance programs include job training and placement programs, the jobs one can qualify for rarely provide better incomes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take a Moment to Reflect</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/2007-08-13-take-a-moment-to-reflect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/2007-08-13-take-a-moment-to-reflect/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Even with the best intentions no one has the right to impose a system of thought or action on anyone against their will. Ironically, that is exactly what has happened to all of us as we were born into this world.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is in some ways no different than being born into slavery, in the sense that we come into the world having no say in the system that will govern our lives, and we spend our most vulnerable years being programmed to become obedient citizens and uphold the status quo.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Best Way to Fit In? Don&#39;t Stand Out</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/2007-08-13-the-best-way-to-fit-in-dont-stand-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/2007-08-13-the-best-way-to-fit-in-dont-stand-out/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Grouping is an activity that comes instinctively and automatically to people. It is part of a filtering process that allows us to make sense of our universe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anything can serve as criteria for grouping, but because this is a perceptual-interpretive process; differences and similarities in physical characteristics are the most prevalent. As we learn and grow, we also associate ideas and experiences with the items in our cognitive inventory.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We give values to people, places and things based on personal experience, inherited attitudes and beliefs, and assumptions. Part of our ability to form instant impressions and make immediate judgments is based upon preconception&amp;ndash;ideas we have formed previously.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Being at Odds with Life</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/2007-08-09-being-at-odds-with-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/2007-08-09-being-at-odds-with-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I never imagined that I had a monopoly on being at odds with life. It is simply a state of being with which I am much too familiar. I have spent most of my life struggling with things that most people take for granted, stumbling and falling in places where most people stride with confidence and conviction. Strangely, I can dance through other places where most people crawl along blindly in fear and confusion or turn and run from in terror. I am not like everyone else, and I can not just be like everyone else and do what everyone else does. In order to live like other people, I have to learn the role and act the part &amp;ndash; but the performance I put on never ends and by going through the motions I end up not having a life of my own.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Price of Admission</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/2007-08-06-the-price-of-admission/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/2007-08-06-the-price-of-admission/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What is a society, what is it made up of and how does it work? The simple answer is, jobs. Society is all about jobs. Living in the wild, surviving on their own, human beings had no jobs. Their lives were defined by the tasks that needed to be done in order to be able to survive.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A bunch of people living together and sharing their resources does a better job of surviving, and each person becomes primarily responsible for the task he or she is best suited to do.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
