<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Intent on eyeofparadox.com [eyeofparadox.wordpress.com] to eyeofparadox.github.io</title>
    <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/tags/intent/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Intent on eyeofparadox.com [eyeofparadox.wordpress.com] to eyeofparadox.github.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://eyeofparadox.github.io/tags/intent/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Point about Paradox</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2010/12/2010-12-06-a-point-about-paradox/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2010/12/2010-12-06-a-point-about-paradox/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the eternal moment, the past and the future are simply a matter of perspective and the past can be influenced by overlapping reinforcement or the intent of the resolving future. A time paradox is a self-informing sequence within a point.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The classic grandfather paradox assumes that time is linear, ignoring the fact that the appearance of a person from the future is an unprecedented event at that point in the past. It also ignores the consequences of his absence from the point of his departure in the future.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impulse</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/07/2009-07-25-impulse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/07/2009-07-25-impulse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Who am I? Why am I here? What is the point of my existence? These are questions we all ask at some point in our lives, and we can go our entire lives without knowing the answer. I suspect that a lot of people try to avoid thinking about it, not knowing how to begin answering, and I wonder how long a person can go without asking them. There are an endless number of situations and circumstances that can force us to confront these questions, and other soul searching questions like them. For me, the question can come up as a result of gender issues, but I&amp;rsquo;ve had it come up in many other circumstances. The answers, whatever they are, test the limits of my understanding, because in many ways I am the awareness brought into focus by both the sum and the gestalt of my understanding. In the scope of my understanding, I am aware that I am not driven by a desire to be female. I am driven by an impulse that is at once too simple and too complex for words, because words will never serve to express that impulse. Because I found myself in a body that I was not able to express myself properly in, it was only natural for me to become obsessed with finding a better way to express myself. I put a lot of thought and effort into figuring out the best way to embody myself in human terms, and because I was thinking in human terms, my self image is based on understanding the compromises that allowed me to be as true to myself as possible. Of course, human limitations are based on the limitations of reality, which are the perceived limits of existence &amp;ndash; or rather the limits of perception. The plain, simple and painful truth is that I am driven to do something that can not be done within those limits &amp;ndash; as we understand them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
