<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Reflection on eyeofparadox.com [eyeofparadox.wordpress.com] to eyeofparadox.github.io</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/categories/reflection/</link><description>Recent content in Reflection on eyeofparadox.com [eyeofparadox.wordpress.com] to eyeofparadox.github.io</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://eyeofparadox.github.io/categories/reflection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Taking Part in the Dance with our Eyes Closed</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2016/08/taking-part-in-the-dance-with-our-eyes-closed/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2016/08/taking-part-in-the-dance-with-our-eyes-closed/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Writing is the embodiment of aspiration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It begins with the will to overcome the unanswerable statement of a blank page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It proceeds in the blind ambition of being read and comprehended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It strives to commit to a more permanent memory the thoughts and ideas of the writer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As often as not, the written word is as quirky and unreliable as any memory, easily lost or misplaced, often transcended by thoughts that spring in the wake of ages, be they moments or millennia.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>A Spark</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/09/a-spark/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/09/a-spark/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;My eyes opened and this is what I saw. You can in yourself be anything you desire. You create yourself from a point. You define your own existence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A soul defines itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What words cannot define, they can characterize, so that the truth may be recognized as it is encountered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The existence of a soul is absolute, at once all and nothing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The qualities of a soul are both infinite and eternal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A soul is not a question, nor is a soul an answer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A soul is a statement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A soul is an expression, a unique, individual creation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I gazed in wonder, I realized that even before a soul embraces the awareness of other souls, the darkness of a soul embraces the light of other souls, filling the emptiness of its existence with the certainty of others, both as a foundation for its own reality, and a medium for the realization of its self.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Staring into the Face of Truth</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/07/staring-into-the-face-of-truth/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/07/staring-into-the-face-of-truth/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;A story is as good a way to organize your thoughts as anything else,&amp;rdquo; she points out, poised in the shadows in the doorway. I quickly conclude that she is playing the part of my conscience. That, or devil&amp;rsquo;s advocate. Either way, she&amp;rsquo;s me. I cannot say she does not really exist without implying the same of myself. She is in my mind, and of my mind, so I do not look at her. She cannot be seen, not in the flesh anyway, but it&amp;rsquo;s not like I have to look at her to see her. &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s been a long time since you&amp;rsquo;ve done this, though,&amp;rdquo; she observes, watching me carefully. I can tell there&amp;rsquo;s something on her mind. I can feel it. Technically, it&amp;rsquo;s on my mind, but I have long since learned that her thoughts are her own when she chooses to assert herself. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit like being in two places at the same time, a way to step outside my normal perspective and look at what I&amp;rsquo;ve become.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Impulse</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/07/impulse/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/07/impulse/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Who am I? Why am I here? What is the point of my existence? These are questions we all ask at some point in our lives, and we can go our entire lives without knowing the answer. I suspect that a lot of people try to avoid thinking about it, not knowing how to begin answering, and I wonder how long a person can go without asking them. There are an endless number of situations and circumstances that can force us to confront these questions, and other soul searching questions like them. For me, the question can come up as a result of gender issues, but I&amp;rsquo;ve had it come up in many other circumstances. The answers, whatever they are, test the limits of my understanding, because in many ways I am the awareness brought into focus by both the sum and the gestalt of my understanding. In the scope of my understanding, I am aware that I am not driven by a desire to be female. I am driven by an impulse that is at once too simple and too complex for words, because words will never serve to express that impulse. Because I found myself in a body that I was not able to express myself properly in, it was only natural for me to become obsessed with finding a better way to express myself. I put a lot of thought and effort into figuring out the best way to embody myself in human terms, and because I was thinking in human terms, my self image is based on understanding the compromises that allowed me to be as true to myself as possible. Of course, human limitations are based on the limitations of reality, which are the perceived limits of existence &amp;ndash; or rather the limits of perception. The plain, simple and painful truth is that I am driven to do something that can not be done within those limits &amp;ndash; as we understand them.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>It Takes a Village to Break a Child</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/07/it-takes-a-village-to-break-a-child/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/07/it-takes-a-village-to-break-a-child/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I do not often get comments on my blog; if I exclude the pingbacks, spam and my own replies, I&amp;rsquo;ve received twenty-two comments from ten different individuals since I started the eye of paradox two years ago. Four of those people have identified themselves as transgendered, and like every transgendered person I&amp;rsquo;ve known, it has affected their lives as bad or worse than mine and I do not have to explain myself to them to be understood. For a long time, I&amp;rsquo;ve understood that this condition is difficult or even impossible for people who have not experienced it to comprehend. In order to live with normal people, the &amp;ldquo;cisgendered&amp;rdquo; if I use the term that&amp;rsquo;s come into use to describe those who identify with their birth sex, I&amp;rsquo;ve had to go to incredible lengths to comprehend and empathize with them. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried many, many times to find a way to describe what it feels like to live with this condition, hoping to make it easier for my family and friends to understand me. As I mentioned, I do not always like what comes out when I write on this topic, because it is a very intensely emotional issue and intensely emotional writing just encourages people to accuse me of being mellow-dramatic. I honestly expect most people to be driven away by the things I have written. Growing up, it did not take me long to learn how incredibly unsympathetic most people are about this issue. I was never asked to explain myself. With the exception of my adopted mother, who confronted me when I was six to ask if I wanted to be a girl, no one ever asked me why I acted like a girl. By the time she asked, I knew better than to admit it, since every other time someone noticed I was just slapped, spanked, or jerked around while being criticized for acting like a girl and being commanded to stop. That does not mean I was not asking myself why I acted like a girl. Even though the question was often on my mind, the only answer that ever rang true was the one that the facts denied.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Point Penetrating Points Overlapping</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/07/point-penetrating-points-overlapping/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/07/point-penetrating-points-overlapping/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A number of my posts, particularly the ones dealing with transgender issues in my life, have been written on a long, dark night of the soul. It can be difficult to come back and read what I&amp;rsquo;ve posted and resist the urge to delete what I&amp;rsquo;ve written, because of how dark they are. I have moments when I think, if ever a family member happened to read them, some of what I&amp;rsquo;ve written could really hurt them. That was never the intention, and yet, there is a ring of truth to the posts I am not able to deny. It is an unfortunate fact that I&amp;rsquo;ve been hurt a great deal by people who never meant me harm because of things neither I nor they had any control over. It is not their fault that efforts to encourage my growth and development as a son or brother caused me so much pain; they were simply responding to what they perceived me to be. Our current society is the end product of thousands of generations of people struggling through life trying to make sense out of it. If that resulted in the division of human traits into masculine and feminine, and if the cultivation of gender roles led to a society that could not understand that there was a difference between the things that make people who they are and the things that make them what they are, it is not possible to assign fault or blame to any specific group, let alone a given person. As much as it would have made a difference in my life to have been raised among people who were more perceptive, or in a society that was more accepting of individual differences, I would still have grown up with the more difficult problem of being a girl in a boy&amp;rsquo;s body.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Matter and Movement in Four--or More--Dimensions</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/07/matter-and-movement-in-four-or-more-dimensions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/07/matter-and-movement-in-four-or-more-dimensions/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;These days, it only takes a little curiosity, access to the Internet, and a bit of patience to find explanations of progressive spatial dimensions or examples of four dimensional geometry, such as the old favorite the hyper-square.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the things you will find use analogies like Flatland, or animations which is a way of using time and motion to reveal a higher dimensional object using a lower dimensional cross section.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>A Glimpse into the Eye of Paradox</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/07/a-glimpse-into-the-eye-of-paradox/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/07/a-glimpse-into-the-eye-of-paradox/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;On any given day, a small handful of people find their way to the eye of paradox. Some of them probably just glance at an article to see if it&amp;rsquo;s relevant to the search that brought them here. One or two might actually read something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once in a blue moon, someone leaves a short comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taken all together, I do not see anything to indicate that my words mean much. Is that frustrating?&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Recapitulation &amp;amp; Reflection</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/06/recapitulation-reflection/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/06/recapitulation-reflection/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A person looking at my blog might get the impression that I do not get much writing done, and it is true that there are a lot of things in my life that get in the way of me writing most of the things I want to. The inside dope is that much of what I do write, I am not sure I want to share. Does anyone not afflicted with gender dysphoria even care about transgender issues? I honestly do not know. I&amp;rsquo;ve known people who were sympathetic, curious, interested, confused, upset and even terrified by the topic. It is an uncomfortable topic, and I do not blame people for not wanting to talk about it; and if no one wants to talk about it (except those of us who have to live with it) why would anyone want to read about it? I dunno, but I do have a lot to say about it, and sometimes I do not realize how much until the words start to spill out. Once they do, I begin to find clarity and focus. It helps me to write it, it helps me to come back and read it, and it has a place here in my blog, because it deals with the paradox of my life.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Damage is Done</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/05/the-damage-is-done/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/05/the-damage-is-done/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I wonder what is going to happen next. I wonder if I can hold it together to get a job and move out on my own. I wonder if I can manage to hold on to that job and support myself. I wonder, because I am not really wanted where I am. The only support I can count on, the support of my family and friends, is conditional. It always has been. It has always been conditional on me finding a way to get steady on my own two feet. The irony of that always brings a smile of agony. I know what they want, and that they want it for me, for me to become independent. It is something I do want. The problem is that it leaves me alone inside a life that holds absolutely no meaning for me. This person that I pretend to be, because he means something to his friends and family, means nothing to me. He does not mean enough, to the people who employ him, to have any purpose. He can be replaced by anyone and cannot compete with the living.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>A True Identity is Nothing to Fear</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/05/a-true-identity-is-nothing-to-fear/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/05/a-true-identity-is-nothing-to-fear/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The response I received to my last post, &lt;a href="http://eyeofparadox.com/2008/05/11/conundrum/"&gt;Conundrum&lt;/a&gt;, prompted me to check out the recent posts of the people who commented or posted blogs in the transgender category yesterday. As a result, I became aware of the outcry against the appointment of Dr. Kenneth Zucker, Dr. Ray Blanchard, and J. Michael Bailey, by the American Psychiatric Association (APA), to the work group responsible for revising the entry for Gender Identity Disorder (GID) in the Manual for Diagnosis of Mental Disorders. The &lt;a href="http://genderoutlaw.wordpress.com/2008/05/11/the-apa-appointment-of-zucker-et-al-and-gender-variant-children/"&gt;first blog&lt;/a&gt; I read on the subject, posted by Gender Outlaw, struck a very personal chord with me. In addition to being transgendered, I was put up for adoption when I was four and spent a year in foster care while the state attempted to contact my biological father so that he might claim his custody rights. It was during my time in foster care that I was terrorized out of identifying myself as a girl and learned to keep my true identity a secret. It took time to learn how to restrain my natural impulses and act like a boy, and the threat of abandonment and rejection was used to reinforce &amp;ldquo;correct&amp;rdquo; behavior. By the time I was adopted, this conditioning had scarred me for life, rendering me incapable of trusting anyone with my true thoughts and feelings. When my new family noticed my feminine traits and confronted me with questions about my behavior, or offered even a mild rebuke for &amp;ldquo;acting like a girl&amp;rdquo; I was consumed with that fear of rejection and lied to deflect any suspicions.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Paying the Price</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/paying-the-price/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/paying-the-price/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As true as it is that some people are incapable of valuing things they have not paid the price for, the fact is that free money is never free. There is terrible cost for being on the public dole, that is immediately evident when you walk into a welfare community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being on public assistance or living on a reservation, the cost of that free income or housing is having to live in poverty. It provides just enough to survive but not enough to advance. While many assistance programs include job training and placement programs, the jobs one can qualify for rarely provide better incomes.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Take a Moment to Reflect</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/take-a-moment-to-reflect/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/take-a-moment-to-reflect/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Even with the best intentions no one has the right to impose a system of thought or action on anyone against their will. Ironically, that is exactly what has happened to all of us as we were born into this world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is in some ways no different than being born into slavery, in the sense that we come into the world having no say in the system that will govern our lives, and we spend our most vulnerable years being programmed to become obedient citizens and uphold the status quo.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>