<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mind on eyeofparadox.com [eyeofparadox.wordpress.com] to eyeofparadox.github.io</title>
    <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/categories/mind/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mind on eyeofparadox.com [eyeofparadox.wordpress.com] to eyeofparadox.github.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://eyeofparadox.github.io/categories/mind/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Examples of the 4th Dimension</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2018/09/2018-09-16-examples-of-the-4th-dimension/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2018/09/2018-09-16-examples-of-the-4th-dimension/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a thought that just popped into my head after reviewing my last post. Right off the top of my head, I picked out two candidates for the fourth dimension of space; Scale and State.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The underlying principle used to distinguish them was a concept that is spatial in nature, that lies beyond the immediate scope of a volume.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Technically speaking, a four dimensional space can theoretically contain an infinite number of volumes, much the way three dimensional space can potentially contain an infinite number of surfaces; what we typically experience as the expression of two dimensionality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Musings On Physics &amp;amp; Metaphysics</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2018/09/2018-09-16-musings-on-physics-metaphysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2018/09/2018-09-16-musings-on-physics-metaphysics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A lot of time has passed since I had the impulse to post anything; that does not mean I stopped writing my thoughts down! I came across the following on a buried tab in my Notepad++ application. I have tons of random notes like this, and often do nothing with them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I mean, they&amp;rsquo;re not really intended for the average reader. You might not be able to follow them, and I don&amp;rsquo;t really know what parts need further elaboration for you to grok them. Even so, I can still throw them out there and hope that you will comment or request explanations if you need them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond My Grasp</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2016/08/2016-08-25-beyond-my-grasp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2016/08/2016-08-25-beyond-my-grasp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Advisory:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I sort of choke and swallow hard before posting an article like this on the eye of paradox, in spite of the fact that&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;I have a history of being rather candid about my experiences as a &amp;ldquo;transgendered&amp;rdquo; individual here and on deviantart. I know that many of these posts have the potential to hurt me, professionally, and yet they serve the essential and undeniable need for self-expression that is ultimately the only way I can justify my existence. I would not be surprised to find that these posts drive more people away than they ever manage to enlighten, and shade my other writing with a transferred contempt. I am sure many people who do read through them must think, &amp;ldquo;this has to be exaggerated,&amp;rdquo; though I must confess that my best effort to put these feelings into words fall short&amp;ndash;hence, I keep revisiting them, trying to vent the agony in &amp;ldquo;a whisper of hollow words to dress up the shattering, inarticulate screams of a forever breaking heart.&amp;rdquo; If you choose to read this, to know what I cannot allow myself to show on the surface, just know that I overcome this pain in every moment I manage to present that calm, composed facade. I am not looking for pity, and I can&amp;rsquo;t say I feel sorry for myself; I am not sorry to be me&amp;ndash;there is just no easy way to present myself to you.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Does it ever get better?</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2016/04/2016-04-06-does-it-ever-get-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2016/04/2016-04-06-does-it-ever-get-better/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am well acquainted with the depths of despair; that place where words hurt in every way and never more than when they give the faintest glimmer of the only thing that could possibly be worse than despair:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hope&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hope makes you drag yourself through the hell you’re trapped in when you’re so broken it’s a miracle you can even move.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hope makes you choke down the agony and anguish, and endure whatever punishment life heaps on top of it, for the unlikely and virtually impossible chance you will survive the pain long enough to discover what it’s like to be free of it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Spark</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/09/2009-09-26-a-spark/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/09/2009-09-26-a-spark/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My eyes opened and this is what I saw. You can in yourself be anything you desire. You create yourself from a point. You define your own existence.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A soul defines itself.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What words cannot define, they can characterize, so that the truth may be recognized as it is encountered.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The existence of a soul is absolute, at once all and nothing.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The qualities of a soul are both infinite and eternal.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A soul is not a question, nor is a soul an answer.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A soul is a statement.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A soul is an expression, a unique, individual creation.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While I gazed in wonder, I realized that even before a soul embraces the awareness of other souls, the darkness of a soul embraces the light of other souls, filling the emptiness of its existence with the certainty of others, both as a foundation for its own reality, and a medium for the realization of its self.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
