<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writing on eyeofparadox.com [eyeofparadox.wordpress.com] to eyeofparadox.github.io</title>
    <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/categories/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writing on eyeofparadox.com [eyeofparadox.wordpress.com] to eyeofparadox.github.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://eyeofparadox.github.io/categories/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>WordPress → GitHub Pages Notes</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2025/11/2025-11-19-wordpress--github-pages-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2025/11/2025-11-19-wordpress--github-pages-notes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;export&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Export&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you click the export button in wp-admin/tools, WordPress will create an &lt;strong&gt;XML&lt;/strong&gt; file for you to save to your computer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This format, which is called &lt;strong&gt;WordPress eXtended RSS&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;WXR&lt;/strong&gt;, will contain your posts, pages, comments, custom fields, categories, and tags.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve saved the download file, you can use the Import function in another WordPress installation to import the content from this site.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you’re going to be using a &lt;strong&gt;WordPress&lt;/strong&gt;-powered site, download the &lt;strong&gt;wp-content&lt;/strong&gt; directory and the &lt;strong&gt;wp-config.php&lt;/strong&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Physics in a Distributed, Process Driven, Information-Based Universe</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2025/11/2025-11-18-physics-in-a-distributed-process-driven-information-based-universe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2025/11/2025-11-18-physics-in-a-distributed-process-driven-information-based-universe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implications of Division by Zero and Point Paradox&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thought for the day&lt;/strong&gt;: My mind wandered back to division by zero and it suddenly struck me that, if applicable in nature, it would be the point where a value ceases to be &lt;em&gt;quanta&lt;/em&gt; and becomes &lt;em&gt;qualia&lt;/em&gt;. I did not see it for a while. I got to it by thinking about what&amp;rsquo;s hidden in plain sight in the concepts of quantum mechanics, and remembering a simple-but-paradoxical description of a hypersphere as &amp;ldquo;a sphere whose surface is nowhere, its focus is everywhere, and its radius infinite&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poetry and Figurative Language Paper</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2016/08/2016-08-25-poetry-and-figurative-language-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2016/08/2016-08-25-poetry-and-figurative-language-paper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April 6, 2009&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENG 340 - Creative Writing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dr. Shari Muench, EdD.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A pen and a piece of paper might technically be the only “tools” a poet requires, but there are many “literary” tools at his (or her) disposal as well. In addition to imagination and a little flirtation with the Muse, a poet uses many other elements of writing to craft his (or her) messages to the heart and soul. This paper looks at the works of three great poets, three extraordinary poems, and explores the imagery, metaphors, rhyme and structure that make them so great. Examples from William Shakespeare’s sonnet, “When, in Disgrace with Fortune and Men’s Eyes” (Thiel, 2004, p.311), Robert Frost’s “The Road Not Taken” (Thiel, 2004, p.297), and Craig Raine’s, “A Martian Sends a Postcard Home” (Thiel, 2004, p.308) will be used to discuss the importance of figurative language in poetry and how it communicates to the reader.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taking Part in the Dance with our Eyes Closed</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2016/08/2016-08-20-taking-part-in-the-dance-with-our-eyes-closed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2016/08/2016-08-20-taking-part-in-the-dance-with-our-eyes-closed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Writing is the embodiment of aspiration.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It begins with the will to overcome the unanswerable statement of a blank page.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It proceeds in the blind ambition of being read and comprehended.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It strives to commit to a more permanent memory the thoughts and ideas of the writer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As often as not, the written word is as quirky and unreliable as any memory, easily lost or misplaced, often transcended by thoughts that spring in the wake of ages, be they moments or millennia.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s been a while...</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2014/01/2014-01-03-its-been-a-while/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2014/01/2014-01-03-its-been-a-while/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have spent the past few years chasing after The Job and sliding down to the point where I&amp;rsquo;m scrambling to just grab A job. It&amp;rsquo;s an old, familiar story, and the details aren&amp;rsquo;t really that important. For the sake of my blog, all that matters is that I have not had much time to put my thoughts down, and no time to review or post any that might have been worth sharing. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure when that will change, but I&amp;rsquo;m going to take a crack at it. There&amp;rsquo;s always the chance that my blog could open the door to some kind of paying work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Staring into the Face of Truth</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/07/2009-07-26-staring-into-the-face-of-truth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/07/2009-07-26-staring-into-the-face-of-truth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;A story is as good a way to organize your thoughts as anything else,&amp;rdquo; she points out, poised in the shadows in the doorway. I quickly conclude that she is playing the part of my conscience. That, or devil&amp;rsquo;s advocate. Either way, she&amp;rsquo;s me. I cannot say she does not really exist without implying the same of myself. She is in my mind, and of my mind, so I do not look at her. She cannot be seen, not in the flesh anyway, but it&amp;rsquo;s not like I have to look at her to see her. &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s been a long time since you&amp;rsquo;ve done this, though,&amp;rdquo; she observes, watching me carefully. I can tell there&amp;rsquo;s something on her mind. I can feel it. Technically, it&amp;rsquo;s on my mind, but I have long since learned that her thoughts are her own when she chooses to assert herself. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit like being in two places at the same time, a way to step outside my normal perspective and look at what I&amp;rsquo;ve become.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exercise in Imagination</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/07/2009-07-11-exercise-in-imagination/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/07/2009-07-11-exercise-in-imagination/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just stumbled across a few things I wrote for a creative writing class I took this past spring to fulfill an elective requirement. One of the assignments involved writing a short story based on a work of art found online. I had no trouble thinking of one that sparked my imagination. The painting &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://kyena.deviantart.com/art/Summer-comes-30814005&#34;&gt;Summer Comes&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; by Kyena was posted on DeviantArt on March 24, 2006, receiving special notice on April 12, 2006 as a &amp;ldquo;Daily Deviation&amp;rdquo; or a featured artwork on the popular artists&amp;rsquo; community site.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Price of Dreams</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/07/2009-07-03-the-price-of-dreams/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/07/2009-07-03-the-price-of-dreams/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We never remember the beginning,&amp;rdquo; she said quietly. &amp;ldquo;We pretend not to know why—but then that is one of our favorite tricks, isn&amp;rsquo;t it?&amp;rdquo; she glanced up at me, smiling at my confused silence. With her arms crossed she began to drift about the room, examining objects while continuing this strange introduction. &amp;ldquo;We pretend not to know many things. We can even pretend not to know the truth. The horrible truth. But the beginning?&amp;rdquo; she paused and met my eye in the mirror. &amp;ldquo;Well there is an explanation for that one. We never remember the beginning because there never was a beginning. That&amp;rsquo;s one of those horrible parts of the truth we choose to miss.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It is Where You Can, and Yet... CAN You? On Writing What I Know.</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/06/2009-06-26-it-is-where-you-can-and-yet-can-you-on-writing-what-i-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/06/2009-06-26-it-is-where-you-can-and-yet-can-you-on-writing-what-i-know/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I may have commented on it in passing, and it is something I certainly never miss, but my art and writing have always brought out the real me. In a sense, that is appropriate enough; isn&amp;rsquo;t it a common recommendation that writers draw from their own experiences? I often feel that my escape into fantasy or science fiction has been good for my sanity, but bad for my hopes of a writing career. I could be wrong. I see enough gender bending in books, manga and film. I find it interesting that most cases involve a boy turned into a girl against his will. Interestingly enough, the first time I picked up an issue of Ranma 1/2, I put it back when I discovered that Ranma considered his ability to become a girl a curse. I did not think I could stomach reading about a guy hated having what I so desperately longed for. Months later, I gave Ranma 1/2 a second chance and eventually came to like him and appreciate what he was going through. I became a fan, read all the manga, watched as much of the anime as I could stand (if you&amp;rsquo;ve tried, you know why I say that), and even wrote over a million words of fan fiction. I&amp;rsquo;m still trying to complete volume five; it&amp;rsquo;s hard to give it my attention when I am struggling to hold myself together and it&amp;rsquo;s writing that doesn&amp;rsquo;t pay.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Absolute Truth</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/10/2008-10-03-the-absolute-truth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/10/2008-10-03-the-absolute-truth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The best representation of a thing is the thing itself and yet there are things that we experience great difficulty recognizing in their true form.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The truth is one of those things.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In speaking of the truth, what we have is a word&amp;ndash;and as a representation of a thing, a word provides a label for a concept that is meaningless without an accurate understanding of what the concept represents.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Understanding the true meaning of truth is a challenge because it calls upon itself for validation, which is a logical fallacy. Or is it?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Divide by Zero</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/09/2008-09-18-divide-by-zero/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/09/2008-09-18-divide-by-zero/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Is it possible to divide a number by zero? Conventional thinking in mathematics declares this to be impossible, but this answer is contingent on a point of view. The problem here lies in the normal interpretation of the value of the number zero; a representation of &amp;ldquo;nothing&amp;rdquo; zero is seen as more of a place holder, a number that has no value. By contrast, infinity is a value that has no number. In multiplication, the value of any number times zero is zero. It is like declaring a number in theory. It is like saying &amp;ldquo;no number&amp;rdquo; and when it comes to division by zero, one might as well be saying &amp;ldquo;no division&amp;rdquo; because use of the number zero declares no number of parts into which a value could be separated, including one, producing a value in no parts. The common assumption is that division by zero would equal infinity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gravity in a Distributed, Process Driven, Information-Based Universe</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/09/2008-09-17-gravity-in-a-distributed-process-driven-information-based-universe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/09/2008-09-17-gravity-in-a-distributed-process-driven-information-based-universe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To a curious mind, gravity is a curious phenomenon. The more one pays attention to it, the more fascinating and mysterious it becomes. Today, we have the advantage of having had great minds ponder the mystery and define what can be observed and inferred by studying it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Newton pondered the question &amp;ldquo;why do objects fall?&amp;rdquo; and provided us with a theory of universal gravity (along with his three laws of motion). He essentially defined the terms we now use to describe and quantify gravity, the force that attracts objects with mass to each other.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Damage is Done</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/05/2008-05-15-the-damage-is-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/05/2008-05-15-the-damage-is-done/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wonder what is going to happen next. I wonder if I can hold it together to get a job and move out on my own. I wonder if I can manage to hold on to that job and support myself. I wonder, because I am not really wanted where I am. The only support I can count on, the support of my family and friends, is conditional. It always has been. It has always been conditional on me finding a way to get steady on my own two feet. The irony of that always brings a smile of agony. I know what they want, and that they want it for me, for me to become independent. It is something I do want. The problem is that it leaves me alone inside a life that holds absolutely no meaning for me. This person that I pretend to be, because he means something to his friends and family, means nothing to me. He does not mean enough, to the people who employ him, to have any purpose. He can be replaced by anyone and cannot compete with the living.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is the Point?</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/03/2008-03-01-what-is-the-point/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/03/2008-03-01-what-is-the-point/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am back in school, freshly enrolled in the University of Phoenix in pursuit of a Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s Degree in Information Technology&amp;ndash;Visual Communications. I do not have a great deal of time outside of work to devote to this, so I was naturally put out when the site went down in the middle of a post. Not just any post, but a post in which I found myself inspired to posit a somewhat challenging question. Of course that post is now forever lost, inspiring this wonderful missive. When you strive to do not only what is required of you, when you strive to do more than is expected of you and stumble into a thought or question that has real potential, only to have that effort vanish without a trace, does it not make you wonder if there is any point?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Point Paradox</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/02/2008-02-23-point-paradox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/02/2008-02-23-point-paradox/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“Detailing the dynamics of point paradox has never been easy, but the founding principle is prime awareness, the awareness of one, all and none&amp;quot; she elaborated, settling lightly on the arm of the couch.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Point paradox is initially a question of absolutes. An absolute can be represented with a value of ‘one’, ‘zero’ and ‘infinite’. These values are all essentially equal, depending on perspective.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The evolution of the soul begins with the exploration of this prime awareness, which is initially the struggle of one to comprehend the duality of all and none.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Medium of Existence</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/02/2008-02-23-the-medium-of-existence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/02/2008-02-23-the-medium-of-existence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“A soul is absolute and absolutes are autonomous,” she asserted firmly. “A mind is paradoxical, acting as an inclusive, exclusive and occlusive interface between absolutes, abstractions and manifestations. A mind, with the absolute of a soul as its foundation, is the focus of existence, whether real, surreal or ideal. In short, the mind is the medium of existence, and a single mind can coordinate the disposition of the absolute, the absolutes, and any distillation derived there from.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m not dead yet...</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/02/2008-02-21-im-not-dead-yet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/02/2008-02-21-im-not-dead-yet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The rare and occasional visitor to the eye of paradox will note that I have been absent for the most part from my own blog. Ironically, this is not because I have nothing to say. Quite the opposite; I have too much to say and too little time to spend on writing any of it down. That is my reward for trying to improve my education and hold down a steady job. It underscores the problem of trying to do what is expected of you. I am expected to find my place in the world in spite of the fact that there is no place for me in this world. If you broke me up into bits and pieces, there is some place in the world for each of those parts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Mind Races On While the Pen Drags Behind</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/2007-08-31-the-mind-races-on-while-the-pen-drags-behind/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/2007-08-31-the-mind-races-on-while-the-pen-drags-behind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My previous post on &lt;em&gt;The Paradox of Death&lt;/em&gt; is a bit more stream of consciousness than I had intended. That is one of the things that happens when writing about thinking existentially. I know I am going to have to reassess what I wrote; there are a lot of good thoughts in there, but I&amp;rsquo;m not surprised if people find it difficult to read. I had an idea and just could not hold it in a firm grasp, so the result is a bit of a train-wreck.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Still Scratching That Itch</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/2007-08-16-still-scratching-that-itch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/2007-08-16-still-scratching-that-itch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The whole moving and searching for a better job thing is going slowly, so even with school work, there&amp;rsquo;s been time to write. Maybe I should not say, write, precisely. I have had a bit of time to pound out some new ideas and wrestle with some old ones, and I am coming to an agreement with myself about what I wanted to write, what I actually wrote, and what I hope to get written. I&amp;rsquo;ve actually been working on a group of related stories based on a common inspiration for years, so there is more material for me to draw from than the seven chapters I&amp;rsquo;ve posted.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Touch of Fear</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/2007-08-13-a-touch-of-fear/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/2007-08-13-a-touch-of-fear/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A good scare is like good sex. It is gripping and all consuming for an eternal moment, but once it has washed through you and you catch your breath, it evaporates. Like smoke, it unravels, curling in upon itself and expanding into nothing. Before you know it, only the memory remains.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>That Itch to Write</title>
      <link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/07/2007-07-29-that-itch-to-write/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/07/2007-07-29-that-itch-to-write/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It seems that the itch to start working on a book has come back to me. It has to be an insane impulse, because with school and work I have no idea where I&amp;rsquo;ll find time to actually write anything. Then there&amp;rsquo;s the fact that I&amp;rsquo;ll be moving in the next few weeks and looking for a new job. I know I must be crazy. Of course, that&amp;rsquo;s not a new feeling for me!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
