<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jobs on eyeofparadox.com [eyeofparadox.wordpress.com] to eyeofparadox.github.io</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/categories/jobs/</link><description>Recent content in Jobs on eyeofparadox.com [eyeofparadox.wordpress.com] to eyeofparadox.github.io</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://eyeofparadox.github.io/categories/jobs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fair and Sound: DegreeStory Replies</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2016/08/fair-and-sound-degreestory-replies/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2016/08/fair-and-sound-degreestory-replies/</guid><description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Original publication: December 7, 2013&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Re: University of Phoenix Online&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Associate of Arts in Business&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bachelor of Science in Information Technology for Visual Communications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h5 id="article-1---100-words-answering-the-question"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Article #1 - 100 words answering the question:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id="is-your-pay-fair"&gt;Is your pay fair?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id="fair-but-not-very-fair"&gt;Fair, But Not &lt;em&gt;Very&lt;/em&gt; Fair&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are dozens of great lines in “The Princess Bride” like “Never go up against a Sicilian when Death is on the line” or “Hello! My name is Inigo Montoya. You killed my father. Prepare to die.” The one that holds the most truth, however, is, “Life isn’t fair, Princess. Anyone who says otherwise is trying to sell something.” What is true about life is true about work. I have never objected to working for a living, but as often as not I’ve found myself in a situation where I was living only to work. I’m an artist and a writer, so I am constantly driven to create—but I’ve rarely been lucky enough to get paid for my art or writing. So, I usually had a full time job, or two or three part time or contract jobs just to pay the bills. I would spend eight hours at work, as much as 3 hours communing to and from work, and another eight hours working on projects at home. I would get a few hours of sleep, and do it all again the next day, squeezing meals in when I had half an hour to spare.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Impact of Social Stratification</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/the-impact-of-social-stratification/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/the-impact-of-social-stratification/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re all human. None of us have a say in what circumstances we are born. Pretty much any other characteristic by which people can be defined produces some form of social stratification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thinking about it boggles the mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve grown up with the ideas of caste and class, and tried to understand how anyone can willingly accept being &amp;ldquo;put in their place&amp;rdquo; by the people around them. In the end, I think it all comes down to the perception of power, the ways in which circumstances can be used to dominate society.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Paying the Price</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/paying-the-price/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/paying-the-price/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As true as it is that some people are incapable of valuing things they have not paid the price for, the fact is that free money is never free. There is terrible cost for being on the public dole, that is immediately evident when you walk into a welfare community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being on public assistance or living on a reservation, the cost of that free income or housing is having to live in poverty. It provides just enough to survive but not enough to advance. While many assistance programs include job training and placement programs, the jobs one can qualify for rarely provide better incomes.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Price of Admission</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/the-price-of-admission/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2007/08/the-price-of-admission/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;What is a society, what is it made up of and how does it work? The simple answer is, jobs. Society is all about jobs. Living in the wild, surviving on their own, human beings had no jobs. Their lives were defined by the tasks that needed to be done in order to be able to survive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bunch of people living together and sharing their resources does a better job of surviving, and each person becomes primarily responsible for the task he or she is best suited to do.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>