<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Outcast on eyeofparadox.com [eyeofparadox.wordpress.com] to eyeofparadox.github.io</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/tags/outcast/</link><description>Recent content in Outcast on eyeofparadox.com [eyeofparadox.wordpress.com] to eyeofparadox.github.io</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://eyeofparadox.github.io/tags/outcast/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Point Penetrating Points Overlapping</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/07/point-penetrating-points-overlapping/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/07/point-penetrating-points-overlapping/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A number of my posts, particularly the ones dealing with transgender issues in my life, have been written on a long, dark night of the soul. It can be difficult to come back and read what I&amp;rsquo;ve posted and resist the urge to delete what I&amp;rsquo;ve written, because of how dark they are. I have moments when I think, if ever a family member happened to read them, some of what I&amp;rsquo;ve written could really hurt them. That was never the intention, and yet, there is a ring of truth to the posts I am not able to deny. It is an unfortunate fact that I&amp;rsquo;ve been hurt a great deal by people who never meant me harm because of things neither I nor they had any control over. It is not their fault that efforts to encourage my growth and development as a son or brother caused me so much pain; they were simply responding to what they perceived me to be. Our current society is the end product of thousands of generations of people struggling through life trying to make sense out of it. If that resulted in the division of human traits into masculine and feminine, and if the cultivation of gender roles led to a society that could not understand that there was a difference between the things that make people who they are and the things that make them what they are, it is not possible to assign fault or blame to any specific group, let alone a given person. As much as it would have made a difference in my life to have been raised among people who were more perceptive, or in a society that was more accepting of individual differences, I would still have grown up with the more difficult problem of being a girl in a boy&amp;rsquo;s body.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Slightly Left of Nowhere</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/06/slightly-left-of-nowhere/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2009/06/slightly-left-of-nowhere/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I rarely have time to write or draw, and as my friend keeps reminding me, I&amp;rsquo;ve little hope making a living as an artist or writer. I have to agree, knowing that even brilliant writing and art takes a massive investment of time and effort up front. That seems to be a recurring theme in my life, however. I have never really had the things I needed to succeed in life. I have almost always had a reasonable substitute for the things I lack, which I am sure could have been used to achieve success, if success meant anything in the absence of a life worth living. The hard, cold facts of life undermine my identity and force me to live the life of a person that does not exist. I succeeded in earning enough to live and function as a man, but the process left me with no sense of myself as a person; nothing that I did felt real to me and nothing that I engaged in felt meaningful.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>