<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Distributed-Process on eyeofparadox.com [eyeofparadox.wordpress.com] to eyeofparadox.github.io</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/tags/distributed-process/</link><description>Recent content in Distributed-Process on eyeofparadox.com [eyeofparadox.wordpress.com] to eyeofparadox.github.io</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://eyeofparadox.github.io/tags/distributed-process/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Physics in a Distributed, Process Driven, Information-Based Universe</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2025/11/physics-in-a-distributed-process-driven-information-based-universe/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2025/11/physics-in-a-distributed-process-driven-information-based-universe/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implications of Division by Zero and Point Paradox&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thought for the day&lt;/strong&gt;: My mind wandered back to division by zero and it suddenly struck me that, if applicable in nature, it would be the point where a value ceases to be &lt;em&gt;quanta&lt;/em&gt; and becomes &lt;em&gt;qualia&lt;/em&gt;. I did not see it for a while. I got to it by thinking about what&amp;rsquo;s hidden in plain sight in the concepts of quantum mechanics, and remembering a simple-but-paradoxical description of a hypersphere as &amp;ldquo;a sphere whose surface is nowhere, its focus is everywhere, and its radius infinite&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>A Point about Paradox</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2010/12/a-point-about-paradox/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2010/12/a-point-about-paradox/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In the eternal moment, the past and the future are simply a matter of perspective and the past can be influenced by overlapping reinforcement or the intent of the resolving future. A time paradox is a self-informing sequence within a point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The classic grandfather paradox assumes that time is linear, ignoring the fact that the appearance of a person from the future is an unprecedented event at that point in the past. It also ignores the consequences of his absence from the point of his departure in the future.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Gravity in a Distributed, Process Driven, Information-Based Universe</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/09/gravity-in-a-distributed-process-driven-information-based-universe/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2008/09/gravity-in-a-distributed-process-driven-information-based-universe/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;To a curious mind, gravity is a curious phenomenon. The more one pays attention to it, the more fascinating and mysterious it becomes. Today, we have the advantage of having had great minds ponder the mystery and define what can be observed and inferred by studying it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Newton pondered the question &amp;ldquo;why do objects fall?&amp;rdquo; and provided us with a theory of universal gravity (along with his three laws of motion). He essentially defined the terms we now use to describe and quantify gravity, the force that attracts objects with mass to each other.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>