<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Childofparadox on eyeofparadox.com [eyeofparadox.wordpress.com] to eyeofparadox.github.io</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/tags/childofparadox/</link><description>Recent content in Childofparadox on eyeofparadox.com [eyeofparadox.wordpress.com] to eyeofparadox.github.io</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://eyeofparadox.github.io/tags/childofparadox/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Avonlea &amp;amp; Kzahn - Tern Vesper Lake</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2019/06/avonlea-kzahn-tern-vesper-lake/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2019/06/avonlea-kzahn-tern-vesper-lake/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="images/david-roberson-avonlea-kzahn-tern-vesper-lake-001-2-35-1.jpg" alt="david-roberson-avonlea-kzahn-tern-vesper-lake-001-2-35-1"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.artstation.com/artwork/Yax9YK"&gt;Artstation Post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll let you follow the link for the original posting details. I&amp;rsquo;ve been focused on testing out a workflow for creating the world of Aeirn in 3D for Child of Paradox. Like much of this sort of thing, it&amp;rsquo;s also concept art for the series&amp;ndash;and there is a lot of it on my portfolio and gallery sites. I am still working on the writing side of things too. I use the time my computer is tied up rendering to jot down new notes, sort through old notes, and work out details like the naming of characters. That last is a bit harder than it sounds, because I attempted to write parts of the story at different times and each time I renamed people to fit the roles they had in each version I explored.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Avonlea - Highlands - Island Dawn</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2019/06/eye-of-paradox-annex-artstation-com-avonlea-highlands-island/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2019/06/eye-of-paradox-annex-artstation-com-avonlea-highlands-island/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.artstation.com/artwork/oOBBVL"&gt;&lt;img src="images/david-roberson-avonlea-island-dawn-2x-anamorphic.jpg" alt="david-roberson-avonlea-island-dawn-2x-anamorphic"&gt;ArtStation Post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A quick preface to this post, Child of Paradox already encompasses a number of story arcs, and each thread has gained it&amp;rsquo;s own heading. Those references help me sort through reams of material quickly in my head, but won&amp;rsquo;t make much sense beyond tantelizing hints at the referenced arc&amp;rsquo;s plot. So, this is one of those glimpses that will leave you wondering, more than spoiled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building on notes for the reboot of Child of Paradox, the notion for today is to change the sequence of the following threads: &lt;em&gt;Hunger and Thirst&lt;/em&gt; can be assigned to Dawn (Arden Ava Nova), as a preface to the inception of Avonlea (Morgan Avon Ova Lea); Predator and Prey can be a consequence of the &lt;em&gt;Ghost/Demon Within&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Slain Lover&lt;/em&gt; threads; &lt;em&gt;Inheritance and Engagement&lt;/em&gt; can be a strand linking the &lt;em&gt;Goddess and Girl&lt;/em&gt; threads with &lt;em&gt;Hunger and Thirst&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Daughter Self&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>A Goddess &amp;amp; A Girl [SPOILER]</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2019/06/a-goddess-a-girl-spoiler/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2019/06/a-goddess-a-girl-spoiler/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve set out a number of approaches to Child of Paradox over the years. Even recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve danced around my personal relationship with the evolution of the story, trying to deal with it in the characters&amp;rsquo; context. I have had to know the whole thing to handle the paradoxical influences, in contrast to the perspectives of both readers and characters. Warning of spoilers ahead, here&amp;rsquo;s a glimpse into the story behind the story: In addition to other notions I&amp;rsquo;ve shared, this is a slightly different take on the story. The premise begins with the dream within my nightmare. Within me, my ideal self retreated from reality propping up an alter ego that is in essence a demon. My dream was always a search for a way to be myself. My nightmare was being trapped in a world where I didn&amp;rsquo;t really exist. My demon was originally an angel, but in pursuit of my dream, it became possessive and took a key role in reshaping my dream into a reality where I could exist, though I did not live in it.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Aeirn</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2018/10/background-notes-aeirn/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2018/10/background-notes-aeirn/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve spent the past week or so going through old notes, gathering some of the History and Legends of Aeirn, and sorting out bits of plot, to figure out where Child of Paradox will begin. There is much more to dig through, but this much is pretty solid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aeirn — A world of magic and technology&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aeirn was originally conceived as a world with a magical and technological heritage. The common assumption, that a magical society would not develop technology and a technological society would discourage the emergence of magic, is debated in front of or with the protagonist at some point. She points out that the two legacies were founded in separate eras and in different parts of the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Rift</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2018/10/the-rift/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2018/10/the-rift/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;One of the distinguishing features of Aeirn, the world where my story is set, is the Rift. Created by the abuse of magic, in a string of wars a thousand years ago, the Rift is a tear in the fabric of reality giving a physical expression&amp;ndash;and access&amp;ndash;to naked Paradox, the inexplicable and improbable union of order and chaos responsible for the creation, or destruction, of all realms. It is the chaos of all possible forms of Order; encompassing the order implicit in all forms of Chaos. It is the expression of Perfection that embraces and supports all of the imperfections of Existence&amp;ndash;the shadow of the Absolute. The Rift is like a door into the mind of God, where only thought&amp;ndash;and the soul behind it&amp;ndash;is real and reality is as fluid and elusive as a thought.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Reality Check</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2018/09/reality-check/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2018/09/reality-check/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s amazing how a little thing, like an email, can have a big impact. I received an invitation to open a store at &lt;a href="https://cubebrush.co/david-b-roberson/"&gt;Cubebrush&lt;/a&gt;, and the next thing I know, I have gone and started laying the groundwork for the promotion of Child of Paradox, restoring a ton of inactive social media, building a new Facebook page, registering for advertising, finally opening a Twitter account, and on and on&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At some point, this distraction from the creative work will be worth it, but what a reality  check! I did open that store, and posted a few images for download so I have some kind of content for sale. I got used to doing concept art that was never intended for sale or publication, so there&amp;rsquo;s only a few images I&amp;rsquo;m certain have no copyright issues. To do anything with the rest, I have to track down the rights holders for a ton of images used as background elements.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Journey Begins</title><link>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2018/09/the-journey-begins/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eyeofparadox.github.io/posts/2018/09/the-journey-begins/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This is not my first blog. It is, however, the first time in a couple of years where I&amp;rsquo;ve been in a place where having a blog made sense. I let my art take over while my writing fell to the side, but plans are in the works to bring my art and writing together. The project I have in mind has gone by the title of Child of Paradox since the first ideas formed in High School, so many years ago.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>